What's the best AI business model to
start in 2026? As someone who's been
building AI businesses for the past
three years and has seen thousands of
people start their own inside my
communities, I'm going to break down the
11 AI business models that are actually
working right now. And these aren't
theories. These are proven by real
people who've used these exact models to
quit their jobs and become a full-time
AI entrepreneur. I'm going to show you
how much each one costs to start, how
easy they are to learn, and the
realistic earning potential of each as
well, so you can pick the perfect one
for you. Let's get into it. the AI
filmmaker. With the rise of the insane
AI video generation models like V3 and
Sora 2, an entirely new opportunity has
exploded for AI filmmakers. It's just
you, a laptop, and some well-crafted
prompts. And you're creating cinematic
ads, short films, and branded content
that used to require entire production
crews. And the value here is that you're
delivering production quality video to
businesses in days instead of months at
a fraction of the cost. In 2025, we saw
the first entirely AI generated ad play
at the NBA finals. And we have guys like
PJ Ace who did that going fulltime into
AI film making and landing contracts
with companies like David Beckham's new
supplement company. So this space is
booming and it's wide open to anyone
right now with a laptop and some props.
The cost to start this one is low. The
effort is medium and the earning
potential is medium to high. Number two
is the AI consultant. The AI consultant
is the perfect entry point if you don't
want to actually build anything. You
instead sell what I call an AI tools
audit which is where you interview a
business for an hour or so. You identify
the biggest bottlenecks and time
wasters. Then you deliver them a simple
report that recommends three to five AI
tools that solve those problems. So the
value here is that you are selling
businesses clarity because right now
small businesses in particular are
completely paralyzed by these thousands
of AI tools and options they have and
they'll pay someone to just come in
identify what's wrong and tell them what
to use. So the cost to start this one is
low, the effort to start it is low and
the earning potential is low to medium.
But these AI tools audits are really
just your foot in the door to much
bigger deals and things that you can
sell them. I've actually just released a
full free course on exactly how to do
these AI tools audits in my school
community. There are people who are
landing their first clients in literally
days using the methods I share in there.
So, the link to join that will be the
first one in the description. Number
three, the AI freelancer. The AI
freelancer is the entry point for people
who want to take the building route
where you can learn a high value skill
like no code AI automation with tools
like make.com or n or go into vibe
coding with tools like bolt or lovable
and you build AI agents and automations
and custom internal software for your
clients. One of the easiest ways to
start out and actually find clients to
work with is on platforms like Upwork or
in communities like my own or through
your existing network as well. And the
value here is that businesses need AI
stuff built, but they don't have the
time to learn the tools themselves. So,
you're trading your new skills for cash
while getting paid to learn on their
business as well. So, the cost to start
this is low. The effort to actually get
it going is medium, and the earning
potential is low to medium. This path of
learning to build is also covered in the
free course that I've just released. So,
if you love to tinker and build, you
want to learn AI agents, automations,
and vibe coding, then that first link in
the description will show you how.
Number four, the AI automation agency.
Both the consultant and the freelancer
pathway actually lead down to this AI
automation agency model, which is where
you stop doing all the work yourself and
you start to build a real business out
of it. So, you've got clients coming in,
you've got systems who deliver the thing
to them, and now you're [music] hiring
other people to do the delivering for
you. So, you're the one actually finding
opportunities and closing the deals
while your team handles the building.
This is exactly what I did when I
started my agency, Morning Side.AI, AI
back in early 2023. Cost to start one of
these is low, the effort is medium, and
the earning potential is medium to high.
Next, we have the AI creative studio.
The AI creative studio is the AI
filmmaker model turned into a production
machine using the agency model that we
just covered. So, it's pretty much the
same setup. It's you, a laptop, and the
right tools and a good set of prompts to
get the most out of these image and
video generation tools, but now you're
pumping out high volumes of creative
assets on a retainer for your clients.
So, that could be social media ads, any
marketing content that brands need.
[music] And the value here again is that
you can deliver in days what traditional
agencies will take weeks to produce
[music] and one person can handle
multiple clients at once. The cost to
start this is low. The effort to get it
going is medium and the earning
potential is also medium. The AI content
creator. The AI content creator model is
where you build a personal brand talking
about AI whether that's on LinkedIn or
Twitter or YouTube and then you can
monetize that audience and the views you
get through sponsorships, affiliates and
eventually their own products if you
want to go down that route as well. The
value you provide is education and
sometimes entertainment as well. But the
catch is that the grind is real and
you're going to need to be creating
constantly. And because most of your
money is going to come from
sponsorships, it can take quite a while
to show up and most people give up
before it actually starts to kick in and
you really start making money from your
sponsored videos. Cost to start this is
medium considering the camera equipment
and editing you need to do. The effort
is high and the earning potential is low
at first, but the ceiling is massive if
you do stick with it and get through
those early phases. The AI influencer.
Unlike the previous model, this is not
creating your own personal brand. This
is creating [music] a fictional AI
character and building an audience
around them. So you can think of those
Bigfoot vlogs if you saw them or one
that I've seen is Ja monkey, this
rustifarian monkey [music] riding
around. People running these accounts
are using AI tools to batch produce
content and they let the characters do
the work. So once you posted enough and
you've built up an audience through
funny clips or insightful clips, you can
monetize these views through
sponsorships and brand deals where
companies will pay your fake person or
character to hold their product or give
a shout out. So this one definitely
seems the craziest, but it is something
people are doing right now and it is
exploding. So the cost to start this is
low. But the effort to get it off the
ground is medium and the earning
potential because it's mainly based on
sponsorships is low to medium. Consumer
AI educator. For this model, you find a
specific audience with a specific AI
problem or a knowledge gap and you teach
them how to solve it. For example, there
are tons of parents that are stressed
right now about their kid falling behind
and learning AI and not being prepared
for the new career landscape. You can
create a course on how to prepare your
child for the AI future. Then you use
content on social media to attract the
right people writing about these kinds
of topics. Then you can run free
workshops to convert these into a free
customer and then you can use courses to
monetize. Everyone needs clarity around
AI right now and there are thousands of
pockets of people willing to pay for it.
The cost to start this one is low, the
effort is medium and the earning
potential is also medium. Next is the AI
business educator. This is the same
concept but a bigger buyer. So the
business AI educator trains companies
teams on AI tools. They run workshops.
They create internal training programs.
They upskill entire departments. The
value here is that companies have
budgets for training and they are
desperate to get more out of AI. They've
bought all these AI tools and their
teams are still using chatbt to write
birthday messages or draft emails. And
when done right, this kind of training
is your foot in the door to more work
with that company. My agency,
Morningside.AI, uses basic business
education as an entry point so that we
can sell other services like our AI
consulting and AI development. The cost
to start this one is low. The effort
required is medium and the earning
potential is medium to high because
these businesses have deep pockets. The
AI SAS builder. This is where you build
software products instead of serving
clients directly like an agency or a
freelancer. There are two flavors of the
AI SAS builder. The first being using AI
coding tools to build a traditional SAS
but much faster. The second is using AI
coding tools to make an actually AI
powered software [music] where AI is the
product or an AI SAS. The dream here is
a recurring revenue business that
scales. But the reality is that you need
to build up some decent AI coding skills
or vibe coding skills or have a big cash
stockpile or runway to pay developers to
work on your product until it finally
takes off. Your first version of the
product will absolutely suck. And
marketing a bad product is brutal and
most people [music] quit or run out of
money before the product actually
clicks. So this is not great for
beginners. The cost to start is high.
The effort is high and the earning
potential is medium to high if it works.
Finally, the AI transformation partner.
This is the top of the mountain in terms
of AI business models right now. And
it's where you are a company's go-to for
everything AI education, AI auditing,
their AI development, and their ongoing
support and partnership. This means six
figure contracts and multi-year
relationships. And this is exactly what
Morningside AI has grown into. But the
catch is that you can't start here. You
need to build up to it slowly through
the other paths like AI consulting to AI
automation agency and then to your AI
transformation partner. But once you are
up here, the ceiling is massive. The
cost to start one of these is medium.
There's a lot of work involved. The
effort is high, but the earning
potential is also high. So there's your
map. 11 AI business models all ranked.
And if you want to start one of the two
most proven paths, the AI consultant or
the AI freelancer that lead directly
into starting your own AI agency, I have
a full free course here on YouTube that
breaks down exactly how to succeed and
get into both, no matter what your
background, if you're technical, if you
can code, if you want to code or not.
So, if you're even remotely interested
in starting AI business in 2026, I
highly recommend you check this one out.
That's all for the video, guys. Thank
you so much for watching and I'll see
you in the next