One of the biggest questions right now
in the AI agency market is how to scale
effectively without fully niching down
to a productized service model. And one
of the top contenders for the answer to
this question is the FDE or forward
deployed engineer model that was
popularized by Palanteer. In order to
dive deeper into the strategy and the
pros and cons of it and how it works in
reality, I've brought on Brandon who's
going to be breaking down how he's been
doing at his agency to scale his agency
with a quality of clients rather than a
quantity. This is very closely aligned
with how my team at Morningside have
been delivering for our clients
recently. So, it's going to be great for
you guys to hear from another
perspective, how this is being put into
practice. In this video, Brand and I are
going to be breaking down what this
model actually is, how it works in
motion, and the tips and tricks around
pricing and scoping to ensure that if
you're going to put it into action, it
runs smoothly for you. And I can tell
you this video is essential if you're an
agency owner struggling to get
consistent revenue. I hope you enjoy it.
Brandon, thanks for coming on, man. I'm
excited to get into this. I think this
is one of the most important topics to
be talking about around scaling an
agency in 2026. It's definitely made the
rounds in the news recently. um and all
the startup scenes about using this
model. So, I thought I'd bring you on as
someone who's actively been using this
to uh scale your agency and give us a
source on how this model actually looks
within an AI agency format. I think
firstly, let's just get clear on what
the what a what a ford deployed engineer
is. I think that's the first thing
people are going to want to know. So,
what is a forward deployed engineer?
What is the forward deployed engineer
model? Uh and how does that look when
you apply to an agency?
>> The Ford uh deployment engineering model
uh was first pioneered by Palunteer. uh
they started working specifically with
this sort of methodology. Um there's
also four deployed strategists. So uh
typically it's a echo and delta team
where uh the echo team actually works
strictly with the business side um and
tries to figure out on the front lines
what that team needs and bridges the gap
between tech and the data. And so the
delta team is the tech team essentially,
but they would um also work with the
echo team to figure out how much
inefficiencies that they can sort of
remove or improve processes for. So
linking this to say like the AI
transformation partner model like like
you've said we're going into companies
to do a really deep audit of their
operations figuring out where the where
the blockages are where the where the
opportunity is for automation with AI
and and sort of custom apps internally
and just generally uh where the
inefficiencies are and then handing them
over to the dev team and that sort of
end toend process of like identification
uh development and there might be some
education and training on the back of
it. How is say this different to just an
AI agency doing a like me sending one of
my consultants? We sent two of my
consultants and he my business partner
went out to do an inerson audit um in in
the United States with our MBA uh client
and they I guess they were a team of
four deployed engineers out there.
>> I think the there's a couple things that
make it different. Uh the first thing is
how rigorous the the audit process is.
So um it goes into like being included
in their group chats, being a part of
their CRM, like a member in their CRM.
So you're monitoring a lot of the
processes that happen digitally. You're
also thinking about the product. So
you're not only looking at the processes
that happen internally or externally,
you're looking at what possible things
have overlap um in keeping the product
in mind. So if there's anything that's
repeatable across other clients for
example we target service based
businesses but even more niche right a
vertical within service base would be
dispatching for scheduling for sales
training right so how can we use that
data that we've that we've gathered to
build that product build that scalable
product so I guess this is you could say
in a way a a bit of a a reskin or or
renaming of the the AI transformation
pattern model in that like you've
a consultant. Ideally, the consultant is
like what we've found at Morningside is
like having the consultant like my head
of consulting Nick who is is familiar
enough with the technical side to be
dangerous and to know how to whip up an
automation or a mockup or you know use
claw code to to whack something
together. um to be able to we found
showing in person when we were doing the
inerson audit over in the states uh that
we could go from a week of intense
interviews and really getting to
understand the business to then within a
few days being able to turn those into
rough demos and workable demos to be
able to show them what hey this is what
the portal or the dashboard or the tool
that we've just talked about here would
look like. So you're finding people who
make that skill set and then you're
deploying them into you're sending them
out or digitally sending them out to one
of your clients and are you like
aligning that one to one? So it's one
one one employee, one of these engineer
consultant hybrids that's deployed into
your company and like what's the split?
Are you having them working at multiple
or is it more of a one for one uh setup?
Currently we have it as a one for one.
So uh me and my co-founder and then we
have a small dev team. um we try to take
one client at a time although we could
process multiple clients if we needed to
but yeah with the advent of AI it makes
it so that we can actually build to the
need right so it's counterintuitive to
trying to find a product that meets
everyone's need or scaling at least it's
actually the most unscalable thing it's
very custom so we actually are building
to the need and then they can see those
results right away and provides a lot of
value up front and there's I feel like
there's nothing wrong that. But the only
issue is that it doesn't it's not it's
not sexy. That's for sure.
>> Before we jump into how you sort of got
to this point for the the person who's
maybe at an agency running 10 20k a
month, uh but it feels like it's all
over the place. It's get they're going
from 20 or 30k down to like five and
backing up and it's just really spotty
income. Um and struggling to scale uh
like smoothly, I guess. What is what is
what we're going to talk about here?
Like how is that the medicine to to what
they're experiencing there? How is it
different to what they're currently
doing? Um I know you've got some stuff
to talk about on the Legion side, but if
I'm struggling to scale, um why is this
the the medicine I might be looking for?
If you're struggling to scale, then um
it would be looking for other things
that that client might need. So being
able to get that recurring revenue, I
think that's the first step. So seeing
why they're not coming back, why is it
that is it the customer journey? Is it
the price? Um, and then once you like
lock down that, it's it is more of a
in-depth relationship. So, it's built on
a lot of trust.
>> Essentially, you take by taking the time
to put someone over there, really take
the time to get to know their business,
go through the full order process. We've
found it, too. Like, we'd much rather
have a handful of of clients that we
work with for like years at a time,
which is where we're at right now. Um,
and they just keep paying more checks
and checks and checks because they have
this with the bigger organizations,
there's infinite amount of work to do.
there's always new stuff to to to work
on. So, the connection you have and and
the trust you build up is the solution
to the scaling problem is to be able to
latch on to a few people and just have
like a couple clients that are paying
you essentially big monthly retainers,
but it's actually just for doing more
work. I suppose you could get into the
retainer eventually. Um, but you're
saying that's that's what this this
model offers.
>> Yeah, it's it's more relationship based
like you said. It's um us going out into
the field. So, we're you can't really
build, let's say, an inventory system if
you're not inside their warehouse. So, a
lot of the clients we have, they're
local to LA. They're in Orange County.
They're um even the state of California.
So, we can't really do a lot of these
things through Zoom. Unfortunately, it
actually has to be seen with our own
eyes. And I think with the industry that
we've tackled, which is service based,
they do like actually seeing us in
person cuz they're very visual learners
and they
do see what they want to see. I said
that in my um my predictions vid for
this for 2026. I think people who get
out there in person, there's a a huge
opportunity for these AI agencies and
and AI service providers to get get the
out there in person and meet these
people. Well, like you would not believe
the the relationship that we've been
able to build up with our clients, but
actually getting in person like building
a real relationship where it's like that
mutual respect. It just unlocks a
different level to the game and it's
like we will be able to work with these
people and make them money. They will
make us money for as long as we're able
to deliver on our promises. And that's
something that I think the digital side
of things doesn't really capture fully.
So um I think that's a good sort of
primer on this model and how it's
different. It's you could I suppose for
those who are new to this it's like the
AI transformation partner model is
primarily uh is scaled through using
these for deployed engineers to go out
there and get in person. It doesn't
necessarily have to be in person but it
can be. Um, but by sending a consultant
who's likely a little bit more dangerous
on the technical side to really
understand their business and having
someone who's like the point of contact,
who's super deep to be able to identify
those, uh, those opportunities and then
report that back to, uh, the dev team to
be able to to build those and he's sort
of middlemaning those from there. So,
um, you want to just jump into a bit of
a backstory here on, um, your marketing,
how we go into pricing and stuff like
that. Okay guys, very quickly. If you're
an aspiring entrepreneur and wants to
start your own AI business and you
haven't already joined my free school
community, it's down there in one of the
links in the description below. Has my
full free course on how to start your
own AI agency as a complete beginner.
And you're surrounded by over a quarter
million people who are also striving
towards the same thing. There's no
better place on the planet right now to
be surrounded by like-minded people. And
you get free weekly Q&A with me where
you can ask questions directly to me
about how to start and scale your
business. I'll see you in there. My job
as CEO is mainly to make sure that we
have enough opportunities on the plate
for the people that work for me. So, um
it's a lot of networking, doing speaking
engage engagements like this, but also
connecting with people at a level that
they can understand. So, um that's the
marketing and networking side. Like I
said, we've spent no money on sales or
marketing, but I think the biggest thing
is referrals and like finding leads uh
internally. And I want to just touch on
a little bit too like some of these
automations don't need to be agentic all
the time. So some of our first clients
that we had, they were just purely AI
automation. So it's like digitizing a
form for instance. So it doesn't always
have to be an AI agent. It can just
start off as something smaller that they
think they need or that provide a lot of
value and then after that they're hooked
and then you can basically pitch them
more things and then it can become a
recurring model after that.
>> Yeah, I think a lot of the time the
agent is actually not necessary. Um, and
I've been planning a big AI agents
tutorial for beginners. And I was like,
hm, could I could I have just done this
with a like linear kind of automation
with a classification step or something,
and if the answer is yes, then it's it's
like makes more sense to just do it with
a a more linear like automation with
some AI in it. It's like the the agent
really shines when there's varied input
and a bunch of different options that it
could do with that and and routes it
could it could take that afterwards. So,
that's that's a great point. While we're
there, you didn't quite reveal how
you're getting your leads. You're you
going to networking events?
>> Yeah, a little bit of everything. So, I
was just in Vegas for CES a couple weeks
ago. Um, investor dinners I get always
invited to like once a week. Uh, found a
trash day, bro. How how are you doing
that?
>> I'm a part of a lot of communities. So,
there's one community, AI LA, if I can
shout them out. There's creator
communities here in LA. So, LA, not the
hugest hub for AI. I mean SF is you're
going to be going to be your AI hub but
ALA has its own culture and personality
that focuses more on like creatives um
but also um they like AI too. So there's
a couple of techies in here um on beach
they call it.
>> Okay. So for people in any kind of major
city uh see what groups there are
communities there are around AI and
start showing up in person.
>> I think that's it like there is even
something extreme as just like
leveraging your contacts list as a CRM.
So, just hitting up everyone that you
know, say, "I'm starting an AI a AI
automation agency or something." If you
know anyone that has a business that can
give me a shot, uh, or you know, would
like to get a free audit.
>> Warm outreach, Brandon.
>> Seriously. Yeah.
>> Absolutely. It's a warm lead. So, even
um I'm here, this is my office. It's
called Salt Box, but there's businesses
all around here, and I've been
door-knocking uh to see if anybody would
need help with their business. And most
of these companies are e-commerce
businesses. So um it it goes down to
door knockocking too. So you just have
to put yourself out there is what I have
here.
>> So we got targeted networking events
>> uh warm leads hot lead conversion rate
100%.
>> So yeah basically um yeah it's pretty
pretty small diagram but essentially a
discovery call via countly or you can
even go in person and schedule a call to
do the audit at their business. Uh which
is some of the things that we've done
before. Um and then in that moment you
can build out their mind map of their
business hierarchy or you can start
asking them um interviewing some of
their employees and really get a really
good idea and this is usually like a
this could be from a day depending on
how large the business is to a week or
to two weeks. Um but it's a really good
spot to actually build that relationship
and then also get an idea of what things
you can tackle uh and you can propose
for the next week. I read a a really
really interesting article from A16Z
recently uh called the pelterization of
everything. It was basically talking
about how every it's like back in the
day it used to be that we're like the
Facebook of X or like we're the Uber of
Y and that was what startups were saying
and now everyone's saying we're the
palunteer of X, we're the Palunteer of
Y. Um, and then this was just a
basically a big exploration of like
you're not really you're just like a
you're you're a services company at this
point. Like a lot of a lot of AI
startups um uh frame themselves as being
using this fl for deployed engineer
model. Um but they're completely missing
all the things that made make Palanteer
so good such as the industry that it's
in. There's very very high like there's
lives at stake on these sort of things.
People are willing to pay ridiculous
amount of money. Um, and Palanteer has
their own uh products and they're very
opinionated in the way that they work
with their clients. It's like you're
going to pay us a lot of money. We're
going to set you up on our systems, our
products that we've built and the Ford
deploys engineers are there to scope
things out, figure out what products
from our bag of products are needed and
then uh go and actually set them up on
those and do the sort of tricky
integration works needed. Um, so that's
the that's the role of the Ford deployed
engineer with them and I think that's
important as an agency going into this.
It's not like sure you can afford
deployed engineer to go and uh use that
model to to do the audit to get familiar
with the business as talking about
scaling solutions. Uh you've the options
always been to just niche your agency
down and say we only solve a certain set
of problems or we work with these these
companies only and essentially you are
taking that palenty model of building up
a stack of of like your basket of of
systems that you can sort of hand out to
a given niche or to solve a certain
problem. to be looking at where you can
build your own products um and force
your clients to essentially migrate over
to your system and to be integrated onto
a platform that you've created is really
where I think uh the scale comes from
because you start to instead of solving
the new problems every single time
you're able to kind of repeat solve uh
some of the main problems through that
product and the Ford deployed engineer
is just getting them set up on it. So
that's an important thing to to put a
pin in and you can't just run this as
like a a purely completely general
development and consulting agency
because that will still be difficult to
scale.
>> Yeah, you will always uh start off as a
generalist but then um as you start to
grow, you'll get more into the verticals
that are specific to what the product
needs to be and you'll start to see
those as you grow, which is the best
part about it. And of course then you
can make that choice whether you want to
go that route or stay in that agency
route. So at least you have the option.
>> Right. What we got next? One of the
longest standing pr principles of the FD
model is placing builders close to users
produces better outcomes which sounds
very obvious in in practice but of
course it's very difficult because you
have to understand basically the
business side and why certain things
exist and so can get into politics and
other things but you have to figure out
a win-win situation for everyone. So, I
think that's probably the echo team's
job, but if you're in a small agency,
then you're going to be doing that side
of things as well. So, um if you're in
front of a decision maker, then one of
the first things you want them to do if
they can is build out their business
hierarchy, like a mind map of their
business. Um, as well as if you can't
get access to things, if they if you
have that trust and relationship. um be
able to job shadow some of their
employees, the very like management, but
then also employees that are like front
desk, you know, people who are outside
the company as well, 1099 contractors.
So, you're you're getting an idea now of
how their business works as a whole, how
they get leads, how they convert those
leads, how do they maintain those leads,
right? Um how they make
>> this just comes down to audit process,
right? Whether it's like the more
digital style where it's like okay let's
map out the stakeholders let's figure
out who like how deep we need to go who
we need to interview do those interviews
get the information back map their
processes on a process map kind of
thing. So this is just I suppose for the
inerson it's you can actually do
physical job shadowing and and that's
that's the model that you guys are
using.
>> Yes we actually prefer that. So a lot of
the things a lot of the clients that we
do have are based around where we live.
We are trying to move sort of across
those flyaway states like into different
locations but we really do enjoy the um
personal connection.
>> That's so cool man. Good on you.
>> The next step would be to build a
prototype and propose uh and make a
service proposal on that on the
opportunity matrix that you found. So
quick wins if you found any. Uh I forgot
to mention that in the AI audit you also
figure out their tool stack. So you want
to meet them where they are. Let's say
they're already using uh G Suite, you
don't want to move them over to
Microsoft. Or if they're using a Jot
Form, don't move them over to Tally,
right? Try to keep it all within the
same ecosystem and see if a lot of that
stuff will not will be unchanging. So,
um even if their brand changes or if
their if they decide to uh collect money
a different way, their industry is still
going to be the same as long as their
business stay the same, then you can
still rely on those core technologies.
So, um hence the word data flow. Um, and
then you can start proposing things that
will make sense to them.
>> Can we just get a little zoom in on your
proposal there if people are curious?
>> So, this is uh one of the most recent
ones we did for a med spa in Beverly
Hills. Um, we actually helped with
understanding what is it they would need
to
take their data to the next level. So,
what they were doing was collecting data
from uh, Tally, but none of that was
data was being processed. So we decided
that it would be best to build an
automation around tally and then build
emails and propose that as their first
automation.
>> This is going from like you got the the
FTEEs out there digging around doing the
audit [snorts] and then you're proposing
on one like you just kind of like I keep
using this analogy. It's like when
you're looking for like a roll of tape
you're like going around trying to find
the the edge, right? And so in the audit
you're trying to find that edge. the
first thing that you can like start
peeling so that you can get a foot in
the door. So, this is just looking at
looking at the quick wins that you
identified and going, "Hey, look, we
think this is the best place to start."
Or you stacking a couple in that first
contract. That's a great analogy cuz
there's if you're looking for that once
you find that piece where the tape ends,
you're going to actually build a lot of
trust in that relationship and you're
going to be able to provide them a lot
of value up front um right away. So,
it's nothing too daunting. it will be
and oftentimes you'll have to offer a
discount for that first for that first
engagement. Um, but that's sort of the
risk that you take when you work with
anybody. I feel
>> we see the same thing if it's a big
client as well, big big brand name.
Yeah, absolutely. You're going to be
willing to take a discount on that and
be like, look, can I just get break even
on this just to get in the door? Hell,
can I like do this? Maybe I'll lose a
bit of money, but if I can land this,
the amount it's going to do for my
agency and the the length of the the
relationship we could build off this.
Um, so this is a this is an interesting
point um, strategy wise.
>> So then it moves into development. Um, I
do also want to mention as well, I think
a cool little tip is when you're
proposing, do it in a do it either in
person or over Zoom so you can show the
prototype too. Uh, what that do that'll
do is all business owners like to get
their wheels spinning. So they like to
see what the possibilities are before
they before they buy. So this is
opportunity for you to actually close
the sale. uh whether just show whe
whether instead of just emailing them a
proposal
>> and seeing if they reply back, you're
actually getting them on the call and
then closing it there. So we noticed
that a lot of actually what we do is
pretty reliant on Replet and Zapier and
you can pretty much accomplish a lot of
your beginning projects with just those
two. So you have Replet offering a web
hook to any API which is crazy. If Zap
year doesn't have that built in or
make.com or go high level then you can
pass it to replet server. Um we do
partner with Zapier so we're using a lot
of Zapier inhouse as well but this it
gives us a lot of options um regarding
like what we can do with the tools that
we have available to us.
>> Okay. Yeah. So just walk me through
that. You've got a replet web hook
dashboard. Give me an example of like
how this works around a problem that you
likely to face.
>> Yeah. So one of them was Jot Form. So um
a client that we used a client that we
had um used Jot Form but we needed to do
some hard like pretty heavy duty
calculations on the form that Jot Form
didn't do natively even with all the
plugins and widgets that it had. Zapier
would not be able to do it either
because it would require a lot of
looping. So we pass it over to riplet
and riplet was able to actually perform
with looping from the payload and then
pass it pass the data back to zap year
pre-calculated or already calculated. So
this reduced a lot of firstly costs on
the zap tasks but it also reduced a
bottleneck that zap year had which was
being able to do all all of those
calculations at once.
>> Okay. So it's like this is I mean this
is interesting where the where the
automation space is going of using
custom code to do a lot of the heavy
lifting now that we've got such
incredible coding models. So you're
saying there's any particularly like
grunty parts of the the automation.
You're just like vibe coding up the
automation and then uh making that
accessible via web hook in and zap.
>> Exactly. Yeah. It opens as long as
there's an API connection to it or if
there's um if Zap year doesn't already
connect to it then you can you can use
it. Well, during the testing phase,
you're often looking for edge case
scenarios. You're looking for errors
that might crop up, which they will.
You're looking for different SOPs that
might happen after the fact. So, let's
say the customer wants to make edits to
it or enhance it or there's things that
change on the fly. So, you're accounting
for all those edge cases in the testing
phase. So, you're seeing if the
architecture that you've built is
resilient enough to handle these and if
possible to build SOPs around it that
they can follow to make themselves
sufficient. And then once you have I
would say at least 95% of this ironed
out then you can hand off and go live.
So you would bring it to their side of
the the fence. So you'd be able to have
them sign up for you know Zappier or
have them sign up for replet and then go
ahead and move that code over and then
instantiate it in their in their
environment. So the next step would be
after that they test it you get more
errors and that's where the support
comes in. So support is going to be a
lot of I would say doing more of the
same thing in the testing phase but
understanding that the scope of work is
limited to a certain point. So then if
it's beyond whatever you guys agreed
upon in the proposal then you can start
building for that. But you do want to
have you know be good be in good faith
with it. So um don't nickel and dime for
everything. You want to be able to at
least say this is beyond sort of the
scope of work. this is going to be
another hour for example and then
they'll be able to make that decision
with you.
>> Yep. The support's key um and often
often under under scoped for as well. Um
very easy. I mean the testing is easy to
miss in the scope and be like oh yeah we
just add a couple hours in there for
testing. Um if it's something like a
voice agent that can take a lot longer.
Um, so this is something we're even like
constantly dealing with at Morningside
is is how can we we're basically
increasing prices all the time because
uh it's easy to underestimate the amount
of testing involved and then also the
ongoing support after. So there's
probably a good chance to slot in uh
just the pricing. So uh say for this
first build you're scoping it out. And I
mean, I think for people who are maybe a
little bit confused here, this is like
such a interesting thing to hear from
someone that you literally just walk
into a business, you shadow people for a
bit, you pick one thing that needs
fixing, and then you build automation
for it. It really is that simple. Um,
and people tend to over complicate it a
lot because they're like trying to start
off with the most scalable niched offer
and find the specific thing. It's like
if you come to a company and you say,
"I'm willing to sort of shadow you. I'm
willing to do the work to get to know
your company." and then we're going to
start picking off the the best use cases
one by one. It it really can be this
this simple. Um so I think it's a
refreshing thing for people heading into
2026 to know that this this kind of
model does exist whether you're doing it
in person or whether you're doing your
audits audits online. Um but I love that
you can just like streamline it down to
one pretty chunky automation here. Um
whether it's agents or you got voice
agents in there or just uh straight AI
automation. Uh but it's uh it's really
important that uh people know that this
is the route. If you're a business owner
who's interested in what generative AI
can do for your business, you can get in
touch with me and my team at Morning.AI
in one of the links in the description
below and we can start your entire AI
transformation process going all the way
from the education and training of your
staff to the identification of the best
AI use cases for your company all the
way through to development and beyond.
We've worked with some of the world's
biggest sports teams and also publicly
traded companies. So rest assured you
are in good hands. One thing we've
noticed at uh at morning soap when we do
our audits is when you are working with
a company who's pretty much on their
first step and a lot of the time people
are dealing with people who are are
companies who are not necessarily cuz
say if you make content or if you've
been doing some sort of other marketing
you'll get people coming to your com to
your agency and being like hey I want
you to build X and that's a very very
different client to someone who is like
I have no idea what to do can you guys
help me take my first step into this and
that's the The audit is the the new
website is what I keep saying like it's
their first step into the AI first move
on the chessboard for companies. And
when you take them from that position
just like and do the order properly,
there are so many like ridiculously
simple automation. It might not even be
AI automation. It might just be a like
straight like non AI automation at all
that can provide a huge amount of value
for it. So, do not underestimate just
how far behind a lot of companies are
and you with your like all of you
watching these videos with your
understanding of what AI can do, you've
probably got a decent grip of
automation. You can provide a ton
of value just by taking time to get to
know them. And I think it's easy to go
into and be kind of scared like, "Oh, am
I actually going to find something that
is going to be valuable enough?" And
that's something that even we we face.
It's like, "Oh, some of these sports
teams, they're already quite advanced
with their tech. Are they gonna be way
ahead?" and we go in there and we're
like, there's so much stuff to work with
here. So, if you're scared about doing
the order, if you're scared about
throwing yourself into it, just like
kind of take my word for it, take
Brandon's word for it, is that there's
so much if you're really deal dealing
with a companies on on step one, you
will find so many like basic
transcription, basic automations, basic
classification, basic like drafting.
There's so much there. Uh, and it's so
often so much easier than a lot of the
use cases you've probably heard floating
around where you need this whole like in
to-in conversational uh, AI system. Um,
it's something as basic as like drafting
a contract or something. Yeah, I think
one of the big things like you said is
uh, you may not find anything, but I
think the confidence in knowing the
tools and knowing what's out there is
where you're building your skill set.
So, um, as you build your toolbox of
skills and AI and keep up with the the
news, you're actually going to find
something. I'm pretty sure of it and it
it is a very nice thing if a customer
already knows what they want. But, you
know, uh most of the time they're not
going to really know what they want or
the thing that they think they want is
not exactly what is going to provide the
most value. And um if you do that,
>> that's the inbound ones. They're often
like think they know what they need but
and like a lot of the time you're as an
agency just like okay, I mean they're
offering to pay me for it. I'll just do
it. And those end up being way harder.
Like you get a bit of PTSD from trying
to do those builds sometimes. And then
you realize like how difficult the thing
they're asking for here is. And it's
like there's probably six other things
that you could have done that were way
easier and would provide a much clearer
ROI.
>> So it is important.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. 100%. I see there's like three
different categories of leads. There's
the there's the outbound you reach out
to and they're like kind of on the fence
like I don't really I don't know like
you're kind of trying to convince them
that they need that they need AI that
they need an audit that they need
something. And so those are always the
hardest and most prone to waste your
time. Then you have the the people who
are maybe coming inbound to you or
you've reached out to them and they're
kind of like, "Hey, no, we're ready to
do this. I'm curious and like, can we
take our first step?" And that's like a
pretty good pocket to be in. Um cuz you
can start this whole process with them.
And then there's the uh inbound where
they know exactly what they want and
they're like, "I want you to either do
this or dive into this area." And so
there's three kind of uh pockets of of
leads that you're going to run into as
an agency depending on how you're doing
your marketing. And it's important to
know the difference between them because
uh you'll end up offering very different
services to them. But anyway, let's uh
let's keep it moving.
>> Yeah, I talked a little bit about the
prototype and proposal. There were some
proposal considerations that I was going
to mention. So
>> just on the prototype, how do you so
defining a prototype versus the
production build? Is this like your we
call these like PC's. Can we just get
the core functionality of the build
working? Like that's the biggest
question mark. Are you charging for this
this uh this PC? And it's just like say
for example it's extracting some
information out of a of an image using a
vision model like the whole build is
everything out the scaffolding around it
the app it's built in the testing and
every like everything else around it is
kind of like is a given but it's like
can the AI do this one specific thing in
it and that's what you're honing in on
in the prototype and and how are you
charging for that? Is that just like a
couple grand or just based on the the
estimated hours?
>> It does depend on the client. So if we
are like you said willing to take the
risk for that client then we will do it
uh free of charge but it often times
does come with a retainer um but this
would be removing a lot of the
non-negotiables or roadblocks for the
proposal. So um if they had said
something like this is a non-negotiable
where let's say in their go high level
they needed to send from their phone
number without using a Twilio or
something else. So this would be
something that we research into during
the prototype and if we're able to
remove that roadblock then that could be
the selling point to it. So we it would
be beneficial for us to build out that
prototype um within reason. So of course
a prototype will just be a mere skeleton
um of what it what it could be or what
it should be. So it'll almost be 40% of
the way there.
>> And so you're back to back to building
on this though. You've got your your
audit. You might have scoped that as
look this is going to take I don't know
what like 10 hours and we're going to
charge like x amount or like 20 hours
I'm going to charge x amount per hour
and then after that you're saying here's
all the opportunities we found here's
what we think we should move on first
the cost for a prototype of this so that
we can like essentially what we we'd
call exploration milestones as well at
morning side it's like let's do an
expiration of this let's so we can
properly scope it basically and we'll
give you all the data back on like okay
yes this non-negotiable is available
this this this a little bit of trouble
on this last one and this is our main
concern and that's how you agree on the
final scope.
>> Yeah, I think there's a part of it where
you have to like know that if you're
going to build it there's a little bit
of risk involved but usually if let's
say someone were to find a doctor and
there that doctor knows everything about
their body and they have their medical
records usually they're not going to
change doctors. So after we've done the
audit, we've already invested so much
time into them that it would be almost a
disadvantageous for them to go somewhere
else but also it relies on the
confidence of our team to be able to
pivot if we need to. So uh there's qu
there's like sales tactics we can do you
know saying like is it the price that is
the issue or is it the the is it the
product that you're that you're having
issue with so then we can negotiate on
that.
>> Is this prototype another fee? Are they
paying another like two, three, four
grand or whatever? Or is this going to
say it's included based off like this is
what we've done in order to scope this?
Uh I I suppose this depends on where you
are with your agency. If it's early
stage and you really need to land it,
you may be willing to do this for free.
But if you're a bit later stage and you
might just be like, hey, look, you need
to pay for this. Is that is that where
do you sit on that?
>> I believe with that it it goes longevity
of the business. Um you can start to ask
for a little bit more upfront. I believe
that in the beginning it was a lot of
free work. I think people try not to do
free work, but I think it's inevitable
to do free work for every business. So,
if you're going to start doing this, I
would say don't charge for the prototype
because they're going to people are
going to ask like, why am I paying for a
prototype? But because you have that
experience, you have the ability to
charge.
>> Yep. Yep. 100%. When you can say, look,
this is just how we do it. This is how
we get results and this makes sure that
we're all all winning here. um once
you've got those case studies to back
you up
>> and yeah we pretty much talked about
this already this was understanding
their tool stack and seeing how you can
build that prototype from what they
already know and this is the u getting
the access so understanding the
opportunity matrix this is also part of
the proposal so we'll go ahead and start
here um testing scenarios so I believe
that building SOPs and documentation is
huge being able to get your client to be
self-sufficient will build that trust um
and then you can start charging for
support after it reaches the scope of
work one of the things that we really do
with our clients that they like uh is an
AI unwrapped report. So every quarter
we'll create a report on like how many
hours they've saved, how many tasks they
run through Zapier. Um and they can
actually see it from you know a report
like if it's actually been beneficial
for them. So um it's something that
we've kind of developed in our own
in-house for our own practice but we
think it's something that is really
important.
>> Yeah, I love I love this. I think um ROI
is way like it's kind of like oh we just
set the automation up agents running and
sweet sort of job done. But I think as
businesses start to get more and more
layers and layers of automation and
agents and it's like I think imagine how
satisfying it's going to be as a
business owner. I think in the near
future where you literally have like AI
monitoring all of the oncreen um and
potentially in person like productivity
and metrics so you know like what tasks
are getting done like how much is being
done from your human human team and then
also you're able to see in real time
like how many agents are actively
working. You can see like real time
agent headcount. Okay, we've got like 60
agents working on tasks right now. And
hopefully you'll see that increase over
like a 12-month period. Tasks completed,
like uh tickets closed, uh true like
productivity measuring is finally on the
table for businesses through like AI
screen monitoring and stuff like that.
Um and of course just tracking what your
agents and automations are doing. And
you can attach a uh say if it's a it's
AI appointment setup, uh voice agent or
a speed lead system. Say that each of
those calls took 5 minutes and it would
have taken it's like reach out to a lead
and and qualify them and book them in.
That might have taken after all the
messing around the CRM might have taken
10 or 15 minutes. Once you can start to
track those and be like literally like
minutes saved, I think that's just going
to feel so empowering as a business
owner when you can start to see all of
these gains stacking up. So I think for
agencies the smart play um well one for
you going back to the scalability
question, this is something that keeps
them around, right? like having a report
each quarter that updates them and being
like, "Hey, look, we are monitoring the
stuff. Here's how much our services have
been worth keeps giving them that reason
to to go to the board if they need to go
to the board and say, "Hey, look, look,
this is how much our our investments
returned on us returned us so far. We
can we want to back the back the truck
up and give more money to these guys."
So, I think this is a genius thing to
do, man. And uh more of us should be
doing it.
>> Scaling R and product building. So
essentially what we decided was it would
be best if we moved away from the
demystify AI LLC model that we moved
into something uh that was more
productized. So we created a C corp
called dataf flow pros and this is where
we actually do a lot of our service-
based business under. So um a couple of
benefits to that is that it's niche and
it's vertical to the industries that
we've been working with but also um it
is a core entity. So it allows for
funding and investors to come in to
essentially look at a product and see a
pitch deck and invest.
>> So let's uh just walk through like going
back to what we said before about the
the plague of the the the early stage AI
agency owner kind of off the ground but
struggling with consistency. We're
saying the solution is to find a find a
company that you can work with long term
and take the time to really get to know
their business and then have a uh sort
of gradual drip feeding of like proven
like just stacking up win after win
after win and taking the time to really
find those those lowest hanging fruit
for them to to nibble off to start with.
Um and by keeping them engaged with
things like uh the uh the reports that
you give them every quarter, this is how
you can fight that uh the sort of
crashing revenue monthto monthth by like
okay this quarter we want to onboard two
new clients and if you can just onboard
two new clients via this model you make
the highest necessary suddenly it goes
from having to scramble for like taking
in like five sales calls a day just to
try to keep enough uh just to keep the
lights on. Okay. Also the like the sort
of lubrication of the whole model that
that trust offers when you don't need to
go through that entire like getting to
know them and like the contracting and
stuff when things can be like hey we
need this okay great you just p you the
last contract oh the latest contract
here's the invoice bank paid and get
start you do not underestimate how much
fat that cuts out of your agency when
you have these say you just have four or
five clients that you're working with
longterm um and you could potentially
get them on like we've been looking at
morning side of uh for things like
annual retainer for being their kind of
AI strategy partner that would be
keeping them up to date similar to that
quarterly report like we're going to
assess your company go back to the the
audit back go back to the process flows
um we're going to see if there's any
updates any latest things that we can uh
we can um update you on so there's also
annual aspects of this that we're
exploring is that uh what we've got the
law firm thing here um how does that all
all fit together as well with this
>> there's more so building like legally
binding contracts to our clients
to um formally instantiate that
partnership. So it almost makes them
almost part of our portfolio as um
shareholders in our in our data flow
pros company. So I think that's more of
a powerful uh relationship than is just
them paying us per month. So it gives
some sort of return at the end and
they're realizing that this is not just
a company that's going to go away and
that they can rely on us for any other
solutions. We don't have like C corps in
uh in New Zealand as far like we don't
really have the same. So explain it to a
non- US resident citizen. Um how this
differs from just any other kind of
company.
>> Yeah. So we have a couple different
structures. You have an LLC, UFC corp, S
corps, but unfortunately LLC's uh are
not able to be funded. They don't have
the idea of shares don't exist in LLC's.
Um so ownership is seen differently. Um
in C corps you do have uh board of
directors, shares um shareholders and
stocks. So those can become uh IPOed
type businesses. So the idea for a C
corp is to actually garner investors. So
if you ever see someone uh in Y
cominator or if you go to crunchbase and
you look up a company, most more often
not they're going to be C corp or S
corp.
>> Got you. Okay. And so for your clients,
how does that make you more attractive
to them on it? like why could you not
just get a recurring contract as an LLC?
What's the what's the difference there?
>> It's not so much them that it is the
company itself can actually obtain
funding. So it does a couple things. It
silos off the data that we're the
product that we're building to just the
company. Um so it's able to have some
sort of separation where demystify can
sort of hold sort of the larger um
concept of AI which is demystifying AI.
[snorts] Um, but for our for our
customers or their clients, I realize
that we can also issue them shares. So,
they're they're also mutually invested
in a business.
>> Cool. Love it. That's really interesting
way of doing it. Um, and so for these
clients, talking about products like at
so far from from what you're doing,
you're doing a lot of like sound like
logistics and shipping stuff. Are these
leading you already towards within your
first couple of audits to areas that
you're you're looking to build out a
product or is that not already on the
horizon for you yet?
>> That's going to be this year. So, we're
still looking to build that product um
using the our findings. Um currently
we're running still as that sort of
agency model, the FD model, but I
believe that with cloud code and cursor
and um another example is OpenAI built
Swarm that was an FTE project. So, um I
believe that eventually the way the
foundations that we've laid um open the
doors up for those options here.
>> I think a lot of agency owners in the in
the space right now feel a little bit
lost. They're like I don't know where my
like the agency model is not the be all
end all guys. Like we've I've never said
that. I've said it's a stepping stone.
It gives you the like cash flow. It
gives you the skills and experience
understanding of how I can help business
to shoot for anything. If you want to go
into coaching, if you want to go into
SAS, if you want to become an investor,
it's the springboard from there. And
it's tough for people sometimes to be
like, they're always looking for the
most scalable thing. It's like, oh, my
business isn't like, I haven't found the
most scalable offer. And it's like those
people don't tend to make it because
they can't just sit in the pain of well
you should be trying to streamline the
business of course but they can't sit in
the pain of the hard work of doing
project after project that isn't super
scalable so that you can build up your
like work on your your dev team's
experience you can like start to feel
out different niches you can slowly
build relationships because I can tell
you from from our experience the best
opportunities for like when we look at
products from our our current clients
and from the work we've It's from the
ones we've been working with for the
longest where you really like you
understand that industry just as well if
not better than better than them in
terms of like how how the the businesses
actually work especially from a
technical standpoint. So if you're not
willing to go through that tough period
of uh like teething and and being being
kind of general uh not feeling super
scalable, you're not going to get to the
point where you can have one of these
long-term clients that really can reveal
and help you help you to see as well.
Like they will kind of point it out to
you. uh the product opportunities that
will will make you rich like
generational wealth kind of rich and so
people like people like yourself I'm I'm
super bullish on that you can sit like
this uh I mean just do the d do the
tough work um until you find that
opportunity because it doesn't happen
overnight I can tell you that much
>> yeah you have to reframe your idea of
what long-term means and um instant
gratification is not something that this
is this is not instant gratification
model uh it's providing value and being
fulfilled every okay, doing what you do
and then with the hopes of having a
product, but maybe maybe we don't find a
product. So, it's it's really about
trusting the companies that you're with
and building those relationships and
having fun while doing it. So, um I
don't think it's for everybody, but I
think for the people who do find the FD
model, they're going to find out that it
does bring a lot of purpose and meaning
to life. And so, um I encourage everyone
to at least try it and put themselves
out there. And um it will be a lot of
learning. You're going to up your skills
and at the end of the day there's a lot
of jobs that uh are FTE jobs that are
coming out. So you can easily get
something like that and it pays really
well.
>> Interesting thing on this is that when
you look at like the most the guys who
are like scaling their AI agencies the
hardest. They've niched down to
something like AI lead genen that like
every business needs this. They've done
like AI lead gen 4x like that that was
already a like lead gen was already a
business. They've just kind of like
strapped AI onto it. Of course, it's
going to be a lot more scalable, but
they I feel like they're trading in the
the short term for the long term because
like you're going to go into logistics
and find some incredible product idea
and make $100 million and they're just
going to make like 100 grand, 200 grand
a month with their AI legion agency and
they're going to find an opportunity,
but like it's nothing that revolutionary
about like there's going to be so many
AI lead genen related like that whole
pipeline is pretty much standardized.
Like you're just putting AI in a
different piece of the puzzle. It's like
conversational AI pipeline to catch
things that fall through the cracks that
that might make you money in the short
term, but it's like like the long-term
opportunities and and the uh potential
of it. You're just like I think the real
money-making opportunities is sitting in
these in these industries that no one's
really looking at getting hands on doing
exactly what you're doing, Brandon. Um
and finding the uh finding the software
opportunities or even it might be like
licensing model. There's just much
bigger stuff that is is waiting to be
discovered um by agencies out there. So,
I'd really urge people to ask a question
of whether they want the short-term cash
or the or the $100 million exit because
that's really what you're picking
between here. So, Brandon, mate, thank
you so much for coming on um for sharing
this course
>> um for going out there and and really
putting this stuff into into action. I
love seeing people take what we've uh
like the AI transformation partner model
and you're you're really putting your
own stamp on it here with uh taking that
palent style model with it. If you guys
want to get this whole board, there's a
lot more source that we didn't really
get to dig into. That'll be linked in
the first link in description with all
of the other resources from my podcast.
Uh but yeah, random mate. Appreciate it.
If you got any last last minute words of
wisdom before we wrap.
>> Thank you so much, Liam. Uh it's a
pleasure to be here and have you driving
me. But um yeah, that's pretty much it.
And uh everyone, I hope you guys have a
great journey. So that is all for this
episode of the podcast, guys. If you
want to see something similar that I
really think you'd like, you can click
up here to watch another one. And
remember, if you think you have a story
worth telling and some valuable insight
you can share with the community, you
can fill out my podcast application form
in the description below. I'd love to
have a chat with you and get some
exposure for your business. Aside from
that, guys, that's all for the video.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll
see you in the next