All right, guys. So, with the Claudebot
dusts finally starting to settle and a
bit of clarity uh coming around what
this thing is and what the potential of
it is, I've had time to play around with
it myself. I've seen what other people
are doing with it. So, I thought I'd
come on here and try to give a bit of
clarity about what I see like where this
is going in my opinion, what I'm doing
at my agency morning side to kind of
adjust for this and what the long-term
ramifications are for this um within the
wider AI and tech ecosystem. If you're
new to the channel and don't know who I
am, my name is Liam Mley and I've been
building AI systems for businesses
through my agency, Morningside AI for
over 3 years now. We work with Fortune
500s, NBA teams, and publicly traded
companies as well. So, I do know a thing
or two about this technology and how it
can help businesses and how you can make
money with it. So, everything I'm
sharing today is based off the context
I've built up over the past few years of
what these new and exciting trends
popping up all the time mean and how to
adjust them basically without losing
your head. The biggest question around
clawbot open claw right now is is this
noise or is this actual signal? Is this
where the market is heading? Is there
something bigger here that we need to
pay attention to? And if it is signal
then what are we supposed to do about
it? The way I see it is that this is a
big deal. Like this is definitely
signal. This is something we need to be
paying attention to because you don't
see things just explode like that for no
reason, right? This is a a clear signal
that the market wants something like
this. The question is, is it super
relevant to us as AI business owners? Is
this something that we should allow to
occupy a bunch of our brain space and
sort of tear us away from what we've
been doing for so long? If you've been
running an agency or AI business for a
year or two now, is this something that
you really need to give a lot of thought
to? And I hope I can give some kind of
clarity around that. The most
significant part about Claude Hub, Open
Claw, or whatever the freak we're
calling it these days, is its potential
to be like the iPhone moment for AI. And
I mean that by it's a new platform that
you can build on top of just like you
had the iPhone, then you had the app
store. How many times have we heard like
this is the app store moment for AI? But
I think this actually is is up there.
It's like the strongest contender that
I've ever seen for this actually being
an app store moment. We have OpenClaw or
whatever the like name you want to use
for it, the actual platform that is on
the device or the Mac Mini, whatever
you're using it on. That is the platform
and then we have Claude Hub which is the
marketplace released by the founder
where you have these skills which you
can easily pull in and install and
expand the functionality of your
personal assistant of your agent. Now,
this is actually a huge deal and I think
skills in general are probably the most
important thing that you need to be
aware of right now as an agency owner or
anyone in AI because skills the way that
they're set up and that that these like
text documents or a couple different
folders and more context or ways to call
certain scripts. This is the the new
SAS. This is bundling of some sort of
functionality and how you can explain it
to your agent just via this little
description at the top. So, MCP was very
bloated. We had to have like tons and
tons of context used up by these MCP
tools. skills are very very smart in
that they're these very lightweight
things that just based off the text
description at the top of the skill can
be they're always fed into the system
prompt of the agent when it's spun up or
your claw bot and then when you're
chatting to it it's able to understand
oh this message is something related to
this skill I'm going to look in and
actually load all the context now so
it's a much smarter way of using context
than MCP was but what skills really
offer is a new route into SAS and I
think if you look at this as a new
platform and cla being the marketplace
with the app store you're going to have
the opportunity to be able to build
essentially a SAS in a skill and skills
become SAS in a certain way. So there's
a bunch of different angles you could go
with it, but essentially the barrier to
entry for SAS is going to drop massively
because there's people who are trying to
build SAS right now. You need to have an
interface and you need to build your
backend functionality and you have to
host it on this thing and like go
through all the UIUX design. And if
you're looking at this through QuadBot,
you can just have a signup page. You can
say, "Hey, this is a great example I
think is a a skill that would be a
YouTube uh video transcript generator."
So using a a proper transcription method
like OpenAI whisper rather than just
sort of stripping it off the captions
which is usually quite garbage. A lot of
people are going to need that utility of
being able to hey can you please get the
transcript from this YouTube video but I
want a high quality transcription
because I want my resulting content to
be good like garbage in garbage out. And
so say I go and vibe code up a YouTube
transcription as a service tool. I put a
little landing page up and I say hey
sign up here. They pay $9 a month and
then I give them their API key. then
they can integrate the skill and the API
key into the claude bot. Now they have
access to this high quality
transcription service. I didn't have to
build out some fancy well it's probably
not the best example for a UI uh needing
UI being a transcription service but you
get what I mean in that now you just
need to build some valuable backend
functionality people would want to hook
into their agent. And so we're about to
see an explosion of these tools because
people can now just vibe code some
backend functionality, put up a basic
landing page, set up a Stripe
integration, list it on Clawhub for some
traffic and to get visibility for the
application and if they can get a couple
up votes, you're going to get natural
distribution. So there is an opportunity
there and I think keeping in mind that
there's sort of skills and SAS and what
this means for these personal assistants
where that goes on the business side if
these are going to be I mean just
because of the security issues I think
it's safe to say that there's a very
clear line between this being a fun
consumer tool and this being something
that businesses are going to look at. So
there's a considerable amount of
development work and security
infrastructure that needs to be put in
before this is even thinkable as a
business tool. uh purely if you're in
this game to make money, you're trying
to build an AI business, you want to tap
into this opportunity and make some
money, this kind of skills as SAS thing
is where I'd say the the opportunity is
right now. Now, the question is, should
you take action on it? Should you give
up the the thing you've been working on
for so long to go and chase the shiny
new object? The best way I could sort of
analogy for this would be building your
house upon the sand or building your
house upon the rock. You know, the the
parable, the wise man built his house
upon the on the rock and the foolish man
built his house upon the sand. There is
always going to be new stuff coming out
in the AI space. This is just the
latest. Like we have these surges every
3 to 6 months. There's a new thing that
comes out. Maybe it's a nana banana
model that comes out and it's way
better. And suddenly there's a a big
burst in and interest over there cuz
there are new opportunities that you
know like I talk about there's fertile
planes. When you have step changes in
the capability of a technology, suddenly
there's this fertile plane where there's
all these businesses that are waiting to
be created. And there's absolutely a
fertile plane that's popped up here. The
question is, is that fertile plane
better than the one that we're currently
on? If you're running an AI agency and
if you zoom out longterm, is that
actually going to take you where you
want to go? My take on this is that
there's a so many problems that need to
be solved in the AI space. There's so
many opportunities like these new skills
of SAS, there's the building on the
clawbot platform. But the bigger
opportunity that is a lot more
unchanging and ultimately going to cause
you a lot less stress and and headache
is the the problem that we've been
solving all along which is there's tens
of millions of businesses out there who
don't understand AI. They don't know how
to use it. They need someone's help.
They need to identify the best use cases
for them and they need someone to build
it and train their teams on it. There's
all of that is still right there. And
you can take the 99% of all the software
that is out the AI innovation we've had
over the past 3 years and they still
need all that. this this little 1% of of
clawbot and open claw in that whole
ecosystem
that's that can be its own thing, right?
That's going to be maybe a flash in the
pan. Something that moves so quickly
that the vast majority of you apart from
the like most technical people or maybe
like the the 18-year-old who's like been
vibe coding and is really like on the
cutting edge of it. You're always on
Twitter. Maybe you have a chance or
maybe that would be a better move for
you to go into this new ecosystem and
really try to establish yourself. But
for the vast majority of people who are
not super technical and who can't move
at the like incredible rate of of
improvement that these things are going
at, then it's not really the the arena
to be playing in for you. You're going
to get eaten for lunch by these people
who are absolutely like crack when it
comes to AI engineering. They're so much
faster and better at building and
shipping than you. So, in my opinion,
the vast majority of you guys need to
like keep this in mind. Understand what
I've said here about the SAS and the
skills and how this is all moving. Keep
an eye on that. But the house that we've
been building for the past few years
still needs to be built. There's still
demand for this house we've been
building. The pace of AI innovation and
these new things coming out of the time
is only going to continue to accelerate.
But what is constant or what is is sort
of unchanging is the fact that we have a
human issue in AI. We have a training
issue in AI. And the where the rubber
really meets the road of hey, I've
identified some opportunities. We've
built it for you. Now we need to
actually get it to stick in the
organization and for people to use it.
That's still the issue. And like if you
want to build a sustainable and durable
business, you don't want to go and build
it on the sand of this new thing that
could be a flash in the pan and before
you know it like open eyes drop
something or applaud or whatever. Uh
which is which is bound to happen. Let's
be honest. It makes a lot more sense to
keep betting on what we've been working
on rather than this new thing. So I'd
rather work with the devil I know than
what I don't. So to bring this all home,
for the vast majority of you who are not
extremely technical, who are following
this like by the minute on Twitter, who
are super deep in that ecosystem
already, if you already have been
working on building some kind of agency
or building a business to help other
businesses through this, I highly
recommend you stick to your guns here
and wait until like build up your
ability to work like so much more
valuable skills is like how to audit a
company cuz that's going to be needed
for millions and millions of businesses
still. how to actually deliver your
development services, how to train the
teams on it. These are going to be
relatively constant throughout the next
few years and all you need to worry
about is how can I use the latest tools
to help me speed up my delivery and then
eventually when we get Claudebot for
businesses, you've got all of these
clients that you can go and roll that
out to. You can add Claudebot as a
service. You can build out a new income
stream or offer based around it as well.
And ultimately, the skills and
experiences you're going to learn in AI
transformation and trying to transform
companies with AI are going to be much
more valuable than, oh, I made a new
little skill or SAS skill on Hub and I
got like 5,000 stars and I made like
$20,000 before like some other thing
came in. And it's like it's it's
building on the sand is the the best way
that I could describe it. And while it
is interesting and I think if you're
interested, have a play around with it.
I'm probably going to jump in and have a
tinker around and see if I could cook
one up. If you guys want to see me do
that so you don't have to, just comment
down below and let me know. And I am
going to be making a few more videos
around how to monetize it if you were to
go down that route. Um there's a few
interesting plays. And after you've
watched that video, maybe you'll have a
bit more context around should I make
the dive cuz it's like do you have
access to proprietary data? Do you have
a certain unfair advantage that would
mean you could create a successful
skill? But the thing is the the revenue
earning potential is not proven for
these. It could be the new app store. It
could be billionaires being made through
this. But it's just such a a risky place
to be playing for the vast majority of
you. So, I hope you can sort of be
self-aware enough to categorize yourself
into one or the other. But that's my
take on it, guys. I think it's really
important that we keep talking about
this stuff because I know it can feel
scary. I know like, man, that that new
surge is just like everyone's anxiety
level just like freaking spikes. But
we're all here. We're all in this
together. The market's big enough for
everyone and it's only growing every
day. So, let's build our houses upon the
rock, not the sand. But if you do fall
into that other category, then by all
means, have a crack. Uh, and I hope it
goes well for you. And as for Morning
Tide AI and what we're doing in relation
to this is basically business as usual.
Like we're sticking to our guns because
we know that what we are the the lessons
we're learning and the the deep niche
experience we're gaining from uh the
work we do with our clients is
ultimately going to be far more
successful in the long run than me using
like you'd expect me with my
distribution. I could be making all
these these skills and pumping them out
to you guys and trying to get you to
push me up on Clawhub, but that's just a
distraction at this point. It's a
classic shiny object syndrome. this new
flashy thing. Oh, maybe it will solve
all the the issues that I've had. Maybe
the reason I'm I'm struggling so much
with building a business is because I'm
not in this new thing. And it's just
guys, you need to stay stick with the
mission, man. Like, we know what we're
doing here. We know why we're here. We
know this massive opportunity that we've
been working away on for so long. And I
just want to give you guys a confidence
of what like I'm not I'm not changing
the strat. I'm not doing anything out of
the ordinary. I'm sticking to my guns
because I have so much conviction that
the the the skyscraper we're building on
the rock over at Morningside, on the
rock of the opportunity that we've we've
tracked from from cycle to cycle to
cycle and we know is going to continue
to be a major piece of the puzzle moving
forward. As this technology races off,
we become even more valuable. They need
us more. And it's it's kind of
frustrating how little we get talked
about. you know, like it's always
talking about the the latest models and
this and this and all Silicon Valley's
up here yapping about the new stuff, but
I can't I don't hear any of the big pods
really like bringing it down to down to
earth and being like, "Hey, well, like
the reason you're 95% failure rates
there is cuz you don't have enough of
these service providers. There's just a
massive gap in the market that we are
currently filling. We're the only ones
there to bring this stuff down to earth
and solve these tricky gnarly human
issues because it's not just a
technology problem. It's not just a
software problem. It's human. It's
change management. It's understanding
the business well enough to spot what
they need. With the way the AI coding is
going, we're going to become even more
valuable because we're going to be the
ones who can fully understand the
business and do the consulting portion,
carry that through, use these AI coding
tools to rapidly get to actual ROI for
companies. And then we do step in again
and we're really needed in the training
piece. It's like we understand the
organizations enough, we understand the
politics and dynamics that we can work
within them to actually get this these
systems to stick. So, we are the we are
the the solution to the AI problem that
seemingly no one is really talking
about. They expect all the SAS startups
to do it when in fact we're the ones who
are in the trenches doing it. Um, and
that's why I'm so confident in the rock
that we're building