Just like we've seen Vibe coding and
Vibe automation, we now have Vibe
editing, which is such good news for
anyone wanting to build businesses and
make money online. So, in this video, I
wanted to bring on Simon, good friend of
mine, who's been absolutely at the
cutting edge of this new trend to show
us what Remotion is, how it works, and
how to set it up for yourself so that
you can start editing your own videos
using Claude Code in just a few minutes.
I hope you enjoy. Simon, mate, great to
see you and excited to get into this.
You've been absolutely uh blowing my
mind with some of the stuff you've been
sending through the group chat. So,
wanted to bring you on and uh break down
how you can use clawed code to uh with
the combination of Remotion to be able
to generate videos uh as if you had a a
really good editor on your team. So,
this is a absolutely cutting edge stuff
and I can't wait to get into it.
>> It's actually nuts the things people
have been cooking up like I have some
demos very recently right here. Like now
you can literally even make Hey Gen and
Remotion. So, you can get your own AI
avatar. You can have motion graphics
happening in the background and all of
this just by you prompting. So
technically you don't even need to be in
front of the screen anymore and there's
like cool explainers on the side. But
you know people have been making like
really cool stuff as well. Like for
example this one where it's actually
let's say nano banana or cling you can
make videos with those and from them you
can use reotion to stitch them all
together and make really cinematic shots
and videos as well right and then people
have also been using it to do simple
stuff like this is for the accelerator
we built with one prompt it even found
your name your logo and stuff like that
and you know make these fun little
motion explainers as well.
>> Cool. Yeah. And so this has all been
made possible through rem reotion which
is what like a plugin. What do you even
describe it as?
>> Remotion is basically a service that
makes video editing or generating any
components or any motion graphics into
code. And because Claude, especially the
Opus 4.5 model, is so good at generating
code, it can take advantage of this new
Remotion service and create any videos
you want just by you prompting it.
>> Right. that's starting to make a bit of
sense. But like, so we have the raw
elements of a video, right? Say it's the
it's the the footage of like an A-roll
of say this a YouTube video that I'm
filming or it's uh the animations that
go on top, it's the the music, the sound
effects. Is all of that stuff taken care
of here or is it mainly just for
basically I have some video files. I can
now play around with them
programmatically and determine how they
get kind of stitched together. And how
does it handle layering on top? So say I
have footage on the background like that
space scene. How does it then put
animations on top of that?
>> Yeah. So ultimately if you think about
it um what are the video editors doing
right and video editors in the back end
is just code. So what you can do with
reotion is when you set up a cloud
project let's say you dump in all your
let's say your a-roll your other uh stat
uh other assets like for example here um
like it actually just like scraped
Liam's your Liam your face and your
stuff and put it in there. So it can
actually take these things from inside
your project because claude can you know
see your assets and embed it where you
need to. So for example, let's say you
have a video of yourself here like this
hijen one. You could just be like hey
can put me on the right and what
remotion does is give yourself the
positioning and layering so you can put
yourself on the right or wherever you
need to. It's essentially like a
codebased video editor if you think
about it. Remotion that's all that is.
Okay guys, very quickly. If you're an
aspiring entrepreneur and wants to start
your own AI business and you haven't
already joined my free school community,
it's down there in one of the links in
the description below. Has my full free
course on how to start your own AI
agency as a complete beginner. And
you're surrounded by over a quarter
million people who are also striving
towards the same things. There's no
better place on the planet right now to
be surrounded by like-minded people. And
you get free weekly Q&A with me where
you can ask questions directly to me
about how to start and scale your
business. I'll see you in there. So, is
there any other theory we need to know
before we like jump into into playing
around with this? Only other theory we
need to know is there are some best
practices into using it. And the way we
do that is by teaching Claude a skill.
And what a skill kind of is and how it
works is essentially like this. Um Liam,
hopefully you're also a big fan of
Pokemon like I am.
>> Yeah, this makes sense.
>> Yeah. So, what we're kind of doing is
like right here in Pokemon when we need
to, let's say, get through water or get
through a tree, we would teach our
Pokemon a skill like cut or surf, right?
In the same way, you can teach Claude
other skills like, "Hey, here's your
video editing skill, and you're going to
be using Remotion to do that, right?"
So, we teach them the skill and then
after Claude learns the skill, it can
start doing these things. And it's
really easy to, for example, like this
TM install these skills because it's
kind of like if you've ever played GTA,
it's kind of like you just having to
enter a cheat code into Claude and then
it kind of just learned the skill on its
own.
>> It's just a command uh that we can run
to add the skill to Claude and that's it
on screen.
>> Exactly. That's it. So, um, just if you
want to make it easier, Liam, I'll send
it to you so you can give it to these
guys. Um, these are what you just need
to enter into Claude and it will just
learn all of it, right? And, you know,
we can get into actually building one
live. So, it's going to be a lot easier
to follow along. And you know when we
want to build this stuff all we have to
do just because and this is why it's so
cool is because the barrier of entry is
getting lower and lower because all you
would have to do is just go to your
cloud desktop app and type into this
little chat box and that's all you need
to do. So let me start doing that. I
just opened up claw desktop. So what I'm
going to do now is I'm going to make a
new folder and I'm going to call this
folder let's say remotion Liam.
I'm going create this and open it. So,
what we're doing right here is we're
kind of telling Claude to build any
videos that it needs to or whatever it
needs to do in here. So, you're actually
really focused. And if you're curious
how to get here is all you need to do is
when you're in the Cloud app, you just
hit this code button and you're good to
go. That's all you need to do. So, this
is just an easier way of using cloud
code. All right. And then what we want
to do is I'm just going to move this one
second. And I'm going to grab this thing
right here. All right.
Right here. I'm going to paste this. And
this is a skill. So now it gets really
easy. This was the hard part. Now I'm
just going to speak to Claude like,
"Hey,
um, I'm trying to create a video for
Liam's AAA accelerator. Can you go out
to the web? Can you search for Liam's
AAA accelerator, get all his colors,
branding, and all that, and then make an
explainer video on what it really is.
But first, before you do that, I want
you to install the skill I have for you
above and then with Remotion, I want you
to create that project and give it to
me. All right.
So, after I did that, uh there is I had
this ask thing because there's ask,
code, and plan. And intentionally I was
really vague with this prompt. So I want
to see where it messes up if it does.
But right here after I just put it to
code so it doesn't ask me for random
stuff. And then I'm just going to hit
go. And then I'm going to trust this
workspace. And you see it just all it
does it just asks you for permission
over and over. So first it installs the
reotion skill.
Boom. Installation failed. Okay cool.
And now it's going to keep doing it
trying new stuff.
>> Damn. So this is I guess the move for
with it like the the clawed codification
of of everything which is kind of what
we're going through here for startups to
be able to create some functionality
that builds on top of or gives a very
powerful new use case to claude code I
suppose is the move but I suppose
there's only a certain number of these
major areas like this that are that are
yet to be tapped right so the video
editing being one I guess you got uh
image gen video again. Um, obviously got
the code side of things already,
document creation. Um,
is this the new move for startups?
>> Honestly, yeah. So, the reason why all
these AI models like Claude, GPT,
Gemini, they invest so heavily into code
and their models being able to code
stuff. It's it's the reason is
essentially because if you can code, you
can technically do everything on a
computer, right? Because everything on
the computer is ones and zeros is just
code. And if you can get that good
enough, you can just have autonomous
people like like what we're doing with
our hands and and our keyboards and
eyes. You can do that and get your
computer to do ultimately anything you
want. So yeah, that's pretty much it.
You just learn cloud code. You just
learn to prompt a little bit and you're
good to go.
>> I mean, the the future of like SAS and
software is an interesting one as well.
like building a SAS and future does come
down to depending on if you actually
need to access the interface or not. But
it's like creating these
functions or external like specific
things that a user can do once logged in
and they can go to set up their account
but the interface becomes whatever
whether it's claude code or or co-work
or this new interface where we're doing
everything from or or chatbt and kind of
like how we had chatbt plugins like
forever ago and that that seemed to be
like the direction it would move. seems
like we've finally come full circle on
on that being the case where as a as a
software uh like a SAS platform, you
want to be able to build a key a set of
key functionalities that can plug into
this and then people won't actually be
using it on your site. They'll just be
paying for the subscription for cloud to
be able to hook into it. That's actually
really good point because like A6 A16Z
they have been investing really heavily
into the the future of the web and they
kind of see it as being kind of aic. So
for example like right now to buy a
plane ticket um for our Africa uh South
Africa event Liam um I would have to go
to Google flights find the best flights
and then go buy it right what A16Z is
predicting is the future of the web is
more agentic based so they won't be
building UIs and stuff anymore but more
so like creating websites and apps so
that other agents can use them and the
reason they're doing that is because
that's kind of what's happening right
No, I don't really care as long as I get
my output. I just tell my AI agent,
"Hey, go find me the cheapest tickets
and then I'll go do it." If you're a
business owner who's interested in what
Generative AI can do for your business,
you can get in touch with me and my team
at Morning.AI in one of the links in the
description below and we can start your
entire AI transformation process going
all the way from the education and
training of your staff to the
identification of the best AI use cases
for your company all the way through to
development and beyond. We have worked
with some of the world's biggest sports
teams and also publicly traded
companies. So, rest assured, you are in
good hands.
>> Yeah. And I guess what we are missing is
the say in this case for the editing use
case until Claude code or co-work and
things like this have a a video player
that allows us to maybe tweak around the
timeline and things like this the very
finetuning uh parts of it.
>> It's just a matter of time until they
add in the layers and layers of UI that
are needed. Yeah. To do these to to do
this kind of stuff.
>> So yeah. So I was actually playing with
this a while back. So you see this is
how it gets generated right.
>> So this is on remotion itself. This is
>> Yes, this is Remotion. Oh, this is like
a voice over, but this is Remotion
running locally. And you see there is a
little video editor that you can mess
with. Um, you can render your videos.
And then there's even like a little
place for your assets. So, right here,
you'll see, you know, this is your logo.
Uh, this is, you know, uh, this is you.
It went and scraped all of it. I didn't
do any of this. And then there's a voice
over.
>> So, it stitched all these together. Uh,
to when you mentioned the assets for the
videos, this is just just about it. It
keeps it here. It uses the assets to
generate the videos. And you know, if
you really want, you can get in and then
adjust the nitty-gritty of it. But you
can also do that by just prompting. I
always think back to like the uh the
instantly use case. If you're setting up
like a a cold email campaign,
>> like what's at a certain point, what is
the actual value of me going onto the
platform and making like a dozen clicks
to set up a new campaign? I should be
able to have my my clawude console kind
of workspace here and saying, "Hey,
let's look at the marketing number that
numbers that have come back from the
last campaign. Let's look at the new
strategy that we're rolling out for this
quarter. Let me pull that data. Let me
look at the strategy. Let me come up
with a new strategy. Plan out a whole
new campaign, new copy for the emails,
new AB test planning, and then just use
like a an instantly tool or integration
to be able to set up that campaign and
basically give the all clear on it all
from just in the chat interface. So the
the SAS platform becomes like the power
of of instantly would be that it can uh
push those cold email campaigns at at
scale and provide you with the uh the
email sending like domains and accounts.
It's really fun that you mentioned that
because we were actually in the middle
of and this is done through like these
connectors and MCPs and we were
literally in the middle of building for
our platform booked in an MCP and we
were experimenting with this but like
now what we were doing is just literally
being like build me a voice agent for
this company and then it goes up does it
and then call them like every day and
then it does it too. So all these little
things are being automated but it's
still going to be up to you to know
which software has the best opinions.
Oh, I think it's done. Uh, but which
software has the best opinion that you
want to follow? Okay, so this video
looks like Oh, it's still going, but uh
let's see. It might die. AAA
accelerator. I guess you didn't use your
colors this time, but
>> complete business blueprint.
>> Yeah, I mean, this is like a oneshot
prompt cuz I made it, you know, learn
the skill and do it. Maybe it's messing
up, but I'm actually impressed that in
one prompt without me even
>> Oh, no, no, no. It's It's getting it. It
got mixed up. As you can see there,
280K. That's my free community. So, it
must have got
>> mixed up in the in the process and like
taken
the the free community information, but
thought that it was the the accelerator.
>> Yeah, probably. I mean, I just told it,
hey, go scrape uh Liam's aa accelerator.
I didn't even wasn't even very specific.
So,
>> okay. And so what does it look like to
edit it from there? If we were to say,
um, hey, just change the change the text
from AAA accelerator to AI automation
agency hub, which is what my free
community is called.
>> You just do that and say, hey, can you
change the text from AAA accelerator to
AI? Sorry, what did you say again? AI
automation agency hub. Okay, let's see.
Let me just be a little more uh
specific. Liam has two communities. Can
you make this to make sure there is no
AAA accelerator mentioned here? more so
AI automation agency hub for Liam.
Um if you want also like these things
you can change you can just be like hey
on can you change the text here
>> uh screenshot if we just take a
screenshot of that and chuck it in be
like can we change number three to scale
to $1 billion a month
>> and for this scene can you make sure it
says scale to $1 billion a month.
>> Uh that's a nice claim.
>> Yeah I'm sure I won't get in trouble for
that one.
Yeah, then now it's also going to, you
know, go ahead. It's going to do its
thing. Um, and yeah,
the stuff.
>> What are the the use cases for this
then? Either as a just a personal
productivity or like another skill, say
like the whole AI generalist thing that
I've talked about. It's it's another
skill that you as an individual can have
power to now create uh video edits like
you have a I don't know 2 three years
experience in in video editing. Is this
just another personal skill that you can
add on or is there the the opportunity
to to turn it into a service and make
money with it?
>> It's kind of a bit of both. So, you can
definitely use it for yourself. Like I
actually I think it was yesterday I
released this video and I edited the
whole thing with Remotion. It just took
me prompting here and there. I generated
all the motion graphics and everything.
So, for your own lead genen, you can use
it to create your own videos and you can
use hgen like the one uh example we saw
before. But if you want to take it a
step further, if you're an AI agency,
imagine SAS companies, they probably
want like product videos. Imagine
marketing agencies, they probably want
like
um videos of their product. Like ecom
agencies, you can use Remotion to insert
those assets and be like, "Hey, I just
made you this really cool ad. Do you
want to do you want like an ad every day
for the next 30 days and you pay me x
dollars?"
>> Okay. So, if we like think about it from
like a I think these like workspaces are
really where it's where it's going. So,
say you're you wanted to start a service
for a certain you could go direct to an
ecom client perhaps um who's running
their own ads or you go to an agency and
you're you set up a workspace for one of
their clients. So, you have a folder for
one of their clients and in there is
like all of the product with their their
photos and sorted by into folders and
you've got the names of the products in
the folders and therefore you can like
reference, hey, create an ad for this
and then you've got their brand pack
which has got the colors and their
website branding and so on. It's got a
text document that has all the
information on their brand guidelines
and and stylistic decisions like
typography um the exact hex codes of
their brand colors and so on. And then
you could brainstorm within uh claude
code itself and maybe have like a like a
plan out a new ad creative and it will
take in into account all of that
information it has there. It might be
able to pick out that particular
product, reference that in the plan and
then be able to generate a new video ad
based off that plan. Correct. Yeah,
definitely. That becomes just like, you
know, it becomes your creativity and
your workflow. Whatever workflow you're
doing, if there's anything where you
need to kind of like change your
graphics around or edit a video, you can
just add this in and get it done for
you. And it makes it a lot easier uh to
essentially just build these motion
graphics cuz you know, the one I showed
you was very rudimentary. I didn't put a
system.
>> How crazy how crazy can we push these
motion graphics? At the moment,
>> you can make fullon basically product
demos. I think you have one one from
Booked in, right?
>> I have one for book 10. Yes.
>> Meet Bookedin, your complete AI powered
sales engagement platform. Let's take a
quick tour of what makes Booked in so
powerful.
>> Uh, I'll just show you this. So, for
example, right here, what it does is I
have my UI and I put it in the same
folder as my Remotion thing, right? So
it grabbed my assets from my UI and
built this this whole uh generation with
my UI components in mind. So in the same
way kind of reotion uh right here maybe
they made a better one. You just need to
prompt it more. But see you can have
those kind of swivels going up and down.
Uh I think there's more. Uh
>> well so I assume they've done all of
this.
>> Yes, they have done there's so many
things that are going on. There's like
map animations that people are making.
You're kind it kind of like the world
you're see this one is also made with
reotion if you can see this like this
map world animation this 3D yeah so it's
kind of it's your creativity oh by the
way I think the thing is done uh right
here
>> let's have a look
uh I guess I just skipped ahead
and so I could get provide information
on which 11 Labs voice to use here so
I've got my own voice it can generate
and what about generating
images and and extra footage on the fly.
Scale to 1 billion a month. There we go.
Great. [laughter]
And so you can just add in logos into
the assets file there and it'll be able
to start inserting those there as well.
>> Exactly. Yeah. Anything you want like
like I don't know if you saw in the
other one, it literally used your face.
So, so the more the more I can stack
into this project file, whether it's
like photos of my team, photos of me,
photos of like successful people, a bit
of like success stories and information
about each success story, like the more
stuff I can just jam into all those
folders, the more freedom it has to like
be creative with those and make better
looking visuals. Yeah, I I will still
say the creative shouldn't be the AI,
the creative should be you. So, um, have
you seen that Rick R, uh, what was it?
Rick Rubin, his, um, clip where he's
like, "I don't know how to play a music.
Uh, I don't know how to play the
instrument."
>> Yeah. But he just knows taste and that's
all you need to be.
>> Yep. Love it. Sweet, bro. Uh, what was
the other I think you have a few more
things on the board.
>> Yeah. So, I want to make sure like uh
you saw like one of the easier things
you can do with we were just making like
really fun, you know, just product demos
or videos right now. But you can also
stack skills, right? And what stacking
skills is, so for example, uh if you saw
in this video right here, this is all
realistic images. This is not the type
of product demo that we were making. And
how this this one is done is by
essentially making a bunch of let's say
Sora 2 or V3 videos and then stitching
them together. So when you're thinking
of Remotions, just make a folder. Let's
say you have a bunch of clips. Just be
like, "Hey, dump it in and be like,
"Hey, organize these for me. Put them
together, put some music on it, and
it'll get that done."
>> Well, okay. But what if I was wanting to
do more of the workflow there and I I
have say I'm working from a brief and
it's like I need to make a a
interstellar themed uh sequence that's
going to sort of dramatically promote X
product. Can it help me to I guess using
just the general like writing ability of
claw code and and the the clawed models
to plan that out into a plan and then be
able to take those prompts and pass it
into a video generator and then I get
those files back within the within the
workspace. Right now what you can do is
like let's say you want a product demo
that's in the interstellar theme. What
you can do is give it the assets and
it'll basically layer it on top. So
it'll generate the nanobanana pro images
and you know that can basically create
anything right. So you create those and
then you take those and then make uh
videos out of that. So for example, you
can take nanobanana pictures and then
put it into an AI image video model like
V3 or cling and it makes that video and
then it stitches it together in reotion.
So what I'm trying to say is like you
see right here there's some like assets
like scenes.
It would take the AI video and let's say
place it here and it can even layer this
stuff on top like these little things.
>> Cir. And you can just prompt your way to
whatever the whatever motion graphics
you want over your over your A-roll.
>> Exactly. Yeah. You can you can use any
A-roll, any assets you need. It's just,
you know, getting the taste and the
creativity out from yourself. It's
basically just a video editor that you
can prompt. That's that's all Remotion
is. But the nice part is that, you know,
you can also just like with cloud code
point it at your assets as well. So you
can make branded everything in your own
theme. So the thing you mentioned with
the marketing brief, if you had that,
what you would have to do is put it
inside the claw.md and the claw.md would
make it consistent and always use that
style or what you're trying to do.
>> Okay. So for someone who's looking to to
get started with this probably for I
don't know their own content creation.
Maybe they're trying to make some
YouTube videos or maybe they're trying
to market their own their own product
and they want to make sort of a a demo
video for it or something. So it's just
getting their uh clawed workspace set up
basically whatever you are. Do you
recommend using the the uh desktop
application or is it actually better to
just use it directly in like in VS Code
with a uh claw code in the terminal?
>> Depends on your level of experience. I
feel like if you're just starting out
100% just go to cloud desktop and then
just use the the code from here because
it makes everything like the same as
claude. But if you're a bit more
advanced, then if you do use VS Code,
you can just see all the assets on the
side and it's a lot easier to manage,
right? It's just, you know, baby steps
into getting into it. So if you're brand
new, just use Cloud Desktop. If you're a
bit more advanced and you know how VS
Code works, maybe use cloud code through
that. That's awesome. Thank you so much
for sharing. I'm definitely going to
have a play around with this and get my
my edit team working on it cuz um
they've been waiting for something like
this for a while. But it's incredible
this like claude code explosion we're
seeing. Um, and it's it's kind of scary
to think where things are going to be in
12 months from now, but appreciate you
coming on, bro. And um, hopefully have
you back on soon for soon for some more
source because um, this this is
obviously just scratching the surface
and um, I'm sure you'll be pushing the
limits of this over the next while. So S
is absolute legend, guys. If you want to
check out his channel, he's dropping a
whole lot of source on this exact method
on his channel over there. Um, but you
got anything uh, any last minute words,
mate?
>> Yeah guys, this cloud code space is
absolutely blowing up. Like literally, I
bought this Mac Mini right here so I can
like build these videos and marketing
assets on the fly on my phone. So, keep
looking into it. Just play around, have
fun, and you know, you'll be good to
take that and sell it to anyone when
it's when they require it. So, with
that, thanks for having me, Liam.
>> No worries, mate. And, uh, yeah, thanks
guys for watching. So, that is all for
this episode of the podcast, guys. If
you want to see something similar that I
really think you'd like, you can click
up here to watch another one. And
remember, if you think you have a story
worth telling and some valuable insight
you can share with the community, you
can fill out my podcast application form
in the description below. I'd love to
have a chat with you and get some
exposure for your business. Aside from
that, guys, that's all for the video.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll
see you in the next