The future of AI assistance is here and
it's not from Anthropic. It's not from
OpenAI. It's not even from Google. It's
from a little open source app called
Claudebot which has taken the internet
by storm. It is by far one of the most
powerful AI tools I have ever seen. And
so in this video, we're going to be
breaking down what it is, how it works,
the dangers and risks that you need to
be aware of before diving in, and most
importantly, the top three ways to start
printing money with this before everyone
else catches on. Plus, I'm going to be
giving away my free guide on how to get
Claudebot set up for yourself the right
way in just a few minutes. So, stick
around for that. All right, Mark. We're
now in the Javas era of AI and uh we're
going to break it down here for you
guys. Not only what Claudebot is, how
significant this is, and how it's really
an entirely new market opening up for
making money and building businesses,
which we'll get into, but more
importantly, like how to set this thing
up, how it actually works, um so you
guys can figure it out and start moving
on it now because it is really taken
off. So, Mark, thanks for coming on,
mate. What are we going to be going
through here? All right. So, I'm going
to walk through how Claudebot works and
what it is. So, you have Claude Code,
which the world, including myself, have
gone pretty insane over. Claudebot is
like a brain that's not necessarily on a
terminal. So, you don't have to
interface with Claudebot on that boring
terminal. And you don't have to use
something like co-work either. So, you
can use whatever input you want. It
could be a Telegram message, a WhatsApp
message, Slack, Discord. You have so
many options on how you interface with
it. And even though it's called
Claudebot, you can actually use whatever
language model you want. So it's meant
to be air traffic control where you get
the message and depending on what tools
and skills it has, it can talk to you
like a chatbot. It can work like an
agent. And most importantly, you can
tell it to be proactive. So if you're
Liam, tell me about the top 10 trends
happening in AI right now. What would be
the most important for my audience? Then
instead of just answering your questions
or doing the thing like claude code
would do, it can do the thing, it can be
proactive and do something else later or
come up with something on its own later.
So this is kind of freeing what you guys
may be familiar with the the
functionality of of clawed code. We're
basically like jailbreaking it, freeing
it from uh being stuck on your desktop
or playing uh accessing it through a
command line. We can now set up a a
telegram bot that we can message
directly. So, whenever you're on the go,
um, in Mark's case, he's bought a Mac
Mini to set this up on, but as we're
going to go into, there's other options
as well, but it's basically setting up
your own special version of Claude code
that has access to a bunch of files and
more importantly combining these skills
in there as well that allows you to
access it from wherever you want. Um,
and this is a massive leap in the right
direction towards uh, like the Javas AI
that we're all kind of dreaming of.
>> And really, the reason why this is a big
deal if your audience is still saying,
"Okay, great. Why do I care?" Why do I
care? because this has gone viral
because it's the first time you actually
have a personal assistant that you can
truly configure and you don't need edit,
you don't need m.com, you don't need a
100 node workflow. You can literally
just as soon as you install it and you
can go back and forth with any AI to
help you, you can build pretty much
whatever you want. So this is the
beginning of the personal assistant era.
This is the whole like the future is
already here. It's just not evenly
distributed, guys. This is the future
right here. And if you can make the most
of it now, there's this arbitrage
opportunity where you're going to
literally be super human for about six
months, maybe even 12 months before the
rest of the people catch on to this.
>> Yeah. So, if people look at this part
where you just send a message, goes to
Cloudbot, comes back with an action, you
might be like, okay, well, this voice
flow thing from two years ago does the
same thing. But there's a big difference
between this and voice flow because the
TLDDR is, like I said, it is the air
traffic control. So, any channel you
want. You don't have to do anything
fancy. Everything comes out of the box
and this is fully open source. Meaning
if you want to change what it can or
can't do or add a different connector,
you don't have to wait for a platform to
do it for you. You can do it yourself.
And in terms of the tools, it comes with
a series of skills like it already knows
how to write Apple notes if you give it
its own desktop. It can create all kinds
of 11 Labs voices and clones. And a lot
of these things that I'm mentioning in
passing were huge edit workflows just
four or five months ago. And now it's
all natural language based. And the fact
that you can even make Claude modular
like essentially let's say Claude is out
of reach financially either for you or
your clients. You can run a local model
and then have that hooked up to this
Claudebot brain and Claude's just the
orchestrator. The Cloudbot just decides
what happens when, which tools are used,
and which skills are needed. Yeah, I
mean the the quickest thing you could do
to cut your cost is jump over to some of
the the Google models, you know, like go
from using Opus 4.5 to anything in the
Google suite. Uh far far cheaper than uh
than the anthropic ones. So there's
that. Or I mean if you're really trying
to minimize cost, it would be the Google
side, right? Rather than having to
purchase the Mac Mini and run the run
the stuff locally. I tried to uh I tried
to run I can't remember what it is O
Lama um and get it to do a run claw code
for me and I've got a pretty decent Mac
and it was just like it took 40 minutes
to generate like 3,500 tokens or
something. So yeah, there is definitely
a hardware limitation so people need to
be aware of that.
>> Yeah, it's a good segue. So the ways you
can use and set up Cloudbot, like we
said, you don't need a Mac Mini. The
TLDDR of why people like myself have
gone one is if you want to have that
interface where you can physically see
that your agent or agents have their own
workspace, their own desktop where it
can build, manage files, operate its own
environment fully, but you want to
separate it from your Mac in your life
so you don't risk hackers, viruses, all
kinds of things going wrong. That's
where the Mac Mini is becoming helpful.
And also if you want to use open source
models like Liam said my computer
basically nukes itself if it tries to
run something on Olama. So because it's
a virgin blank slate technically
computer of its own. You can also run
language models a lot more easily. But
for most of your audience the cloud is
probably one of the best places to go.
You can literally use Amazon Web
Services. There's tons of tutorials
already on this and you can hook it up
on the free tier and you can use this on
the free tier. It just might not be as
pretty and cute as me what I'm about to
show your audience shortly in terms of
how I has have it set up.
>> Love it. So, what you've got what maybe
10 20 bucks a month or we talking like
50 100 bucks a month to actually run
this at any kind of uh kind of scale.
>> This literally free tier like you can
live on the free tier depending on how
much you use it. I suppose it's if
you're choosing to use the like the
Gemini API like accessing it through a
hosted model like self not a self-hosted
model but a provider where they're
already running the models for you and
then you're just paying for the uh cloud
space to be able to run the claudebot
itself right rather than running the
clawbot and also uh hosting the model.
So you want to stay away from hosting
the model uh on the cloud setup as well.
Guys, if you are already sold on Clawbot
and want to get this set up for yourself
the right way in a few minutes, I've got
my full guide on how to do that in the
first link in the description. It's
going to break it down for you so that
you can set it up the right way without
all the risks. Plus, with that resource,
I'm also going to be including a more
in-depth breakdown of each of the
money-making methods for you guys so
that you can take action on them today.
Yeah. And there's one more thing. Um,
let's say you don't want the Mac Mini,
but you still want to run it locally.
You could also use something like Docker
to create a container to run a local
model to also interface with this. So,
it's very malleable because it's open
source and unlike a company telling you
how you have to use something, it's
completely up to you. It's just a matter
of what fits the best for you. Now, in
terms of where mine lives. So, obviously
I have the Mac Mini here. Where it lives
is its own laptop. So, this laptop, I'm
basically rendering this on my actual
screen on my real laptop. It just has
access to its own notes. It creates its
own folders. It manages this system. So
this is technically my agent's computer,
which is why it's so malleable, because
anything that happens here is only
constrained to what's happened here. So
in other words, the blast radius of
anything going haywire won't affect my
finances, my credit cards, or my files
in general, which is a piece of mind if
it's something within reach because you
can manage everything and you can also
manage what's being installed, how it's
being used.
>> I'm even considering the investment
myself now just so I can tinker around
over it over over the next week or so.
And uh once you set it up, it comes with
its own localhosted command center. So
this is the Cloudbot command center.
This gives you an overview over how long
it's been connected, how many instances
it has. Uh if it has jobs that it runs
over and over again in the form of
what's called a cron, when you speak to
it, let's say via Telegram like I do, it
can decide, okay, cool. It looks like
Mark wants to run this reminder to go
check his YouTube competitors and look
at their comments using the app scraper
every hour or every 3 hours. And this is
where the proactivity comes in because
it basically pings its own server and it
messages me whatever I'm looking for.
And then a part of that picture is
obviously skills. So like you have
normal cloud skills, these are all open-
source skills. So these skills let it
use things like the Apple reminders,
write its own notes, watch for blogs,
take a screenshot of its own
environment. So it can be literally be
like, am I doing the right thing? As if
it's like your actual virtual assistant.
>> Yep. So these are a lot of these come
out of the box in the in the setup
wizard, which is helpful, right? So this
is I think a huge leap forward. this is
is that these come out of the box and a
lot of the integrations like the 11 labs
one which we can showcase in a second
but instead of the like clunkiness of
MCPs and now bloated those can be these
skills now seem to be forming as like
the new unit of like integration or as
as a feature and the fact that we'll be
able to like browse marketplaces for
these and figure out what we want to
plug in very quickly to our uh to our
personal like Jarvis here um I think is
is super exciting for for non techies
especially
>> yeah and just the TLDDR for people on
difference between skills and MCP. A
skill is like a constrained set of let's
say endpoints or different
functionalities from a service. Let's
use 11 Labs as an example. If you want
to clone a voice, if you want to
generate something with an existing
voice, those are two different
functions. So, skill just creates a
cheat sheet in plain English with those
functions and it tells whatever LM it
is, this is how to use it and this is
when to use it. And the core difference
is an MCP is kind of always on, meaning
it's bloating your context window of
your conversation, which might push the
agent to time out. A skill is invoked
just in time, meaning whenever it's
needed, it'll be used.
>> Yep. Love it. I think that's future for
sure. And I I think even Anthropic kind
of admitted that MCB wasn't the way
forward um by by making the transition
over to Skills
>> 100%. So um we already spoke about the
cloudbot environment. You can connect it
to whatever you want. Discord, iMessage,
Signal, whatever makes you happy. A lot
of this stuff comes out of the box. You
just have to hook it up. If you choose
WhatsApp, I think you have to just scan
a QR code and it hooks up to your
personal number. So, one disclaimer for
your audience is if you want to separate
your life, which I recommend that you do
if you're not a cyber security expert
yet, it's probably better to use
something like Telegram, especially
because the blast radius of something
going wrong is probably a lot lower.
Yeah. And then when it comes to um where
you can interface with it, you can also
do Google chat, Microsoft Teams, etc. So
I only allude to that because there is a
business opportunity here if you can
figure out how to set this up, securely,
and use it because most of your clients
are using something like that,
[laughter]
>> securely. Yeah. I mean, just like
scratching the surface of how this can
be set up as a as a service, which we'll
go into in a second, is uh it's huge
opportunity here.
>> And then behind the scenes, just in case
you're still okay, let's say you know
cloud code. So if I say the words claude
code then when I say claude MD might
mean something to you. Claude MD is like
the brain of how claude code operates
every session. It's kind of like the the
values the holy book
>> like priming.
>> Yeah.
>> Exactly. Exactly. So the priming here is
a bit different. When you onboard
Cloudbot it asks you questions about how
it should behave. So it's fully going
the personal assistant angle. Literally
ask me when you're wrong Mark. Do you
want me to be direct and tell you wrong
or do you want me to be soft or passive
about it? So, it interviews you in
natural language and then it stores your
preferences in its soul.mmarkdown
file. So, it's literally called
soul.mmarkdown. Then asks you what it
should identify as by name, creature,
etc. So, it out of the box in 15 minutes
once you have it installed, it's ready
to go. It knows how to speak to you. I
told it I like lowercase. I write in
lowercase. Don't give me some cookie
cutter stuff. Don't say I'm absolutely
right. and then we were ready to go.
>> Now, we might have this just after this,
but when it comes to building in your
workflows to this, so you've got your
workspace set up, you might provide it
with uh the some like market research
data or uh sort of key components and
and documents about your business. How
then are you needing to create custom
skills or are there like simple commands
that you can set up? How do you then
start to make workflows on top of this?
So, one tool that I like to use quite a
bit, you can use whatever you want. Any
form of IDE where it can do stuff is
helpful. I like to use warp because it
has a free tier. So, what I like to do
is I just go and I say, "Hey, can you go
interface with Claudebot? I don't feel
like building a skill, but can you go
and figure out how to use insert X API?"
Let's say we want to do the Hen API to
make a copy of ourselves. Go look at the
Hen API. see what you need from me and
see what would it take to make a skill.
Then once it creates a skill, it stores
it behind the scenes and it tells
Claudebot in its like identity and its
tools file, make sure that when Mark
says clone or avatar, we use this heygen
skill. So that's one avenue. Another
avenue is once you have it set it up
well, you can actually ask Claudebot to
create the skill itself. So once in a
while I'll ask it, I have a challenge
for you. I don't know how you're going
to do this, but I have this voice note
from Liam. I want you to take this voice
note and I want you to clone his voice
somehow using 11 laps. I'm not gonna
tell you how. I'm not going to tell you
where. You have the API key. Go figure
it out. So, it will go 5 10 minutes, try
a couple things, then come back and
figure it out. Okay. So, if we pop in,
you can see this is my beautiful
assistant Claudet. I actually asked her
to make her own profile picture and I
asked her, can you tell me what Liam's
last three videos were about? So behind
the scenes I gave it access to ampify
specifically the MCP just to make it
easier. It went kind of scraped it turns
back the link
>> closing quickly on that.
Ampify is a great thing to have
integrated because of it like depth of
different scrapers. Right? So that's
just like a very easy general purpose uh
connection you can make to give your
your clawbot a ton more capability.
Right. So it can find a LinkedIn scraper
if it needs to and use that and it's
just all set up through through your
appy account. You're going to get ping
for those actors.
>> Exactly. So, if you go to, it's a great
segue. Go to mcp.appfi.com.
You could see out of the box. You can
just set everything up. Then you can
click any one of these. This is what I
did. I literally just clicked on warp.
Uh, it gives me the request that I need
to send. Or you could do, let's say,
cloud code. You just give it this
command. You paste that. You tell it,
can you go learn how to use the appy mcp
and then you can add whatever actors you
want. So, in this case, you can just
literally go select them, click save,
then you're good to go. And then
>> so you manually add those in or there is
a like when it uses the search function
there. Is it going to search from the
ones you've enabled or is it going to
search the whole uh the whole database
of of actors?
>> You're asking the right questions. So
out of the box I manually put ones in
that I know for a fact I want always. So
that's where I added them here. And then
you just have to enable it to search
actors and call actors. And then if it's
not there, if it doesn't have, let's
say, a LinkedIn scraper, it can go and
search for an actor that's highly rated
and then add that to its stack.
>> That's super helpful.
>> That's how we got these YouTube videos.
And then this is the part where it's
super cool. I sent it a voice note um
just to better understand what's
happening. And like I asked it, can you
create a clone of the following voice
note that I'm about to send you? So it I
basically gave it this voice note of
Liam swearing at me for being late to
this pod. and then listened to it. And
then I said, "Can you use this file to
clone his voice and send me a sample of
the clone telling me that he loves me?"
Now, I would love to play this, but Liam
kind of muffled his own voice on
purpose, so it was going to sound super
goofy. Do you want me to play it or
what?
>> Yeah, I mean, I I haven't heard this. Is
it my bad American accent? [laughter]
>> Hey, Mark, I love you, man. This voice
cloning technology is absolutely
>> That does sound like how I sounded in
the voice.
>> In the future. Hey Mark.
>> Yeah, Mark. Man, that's what I sound
like. [laughter]
>> Yeah. And then I said, um, can you voice
note me uh a breakdown of Liam's channel
strategy from what you can see? And
super interesting that I want to show
your audience here is
>> that started glazing me immediately.
>> Yeah. I mean, that's part two. That's
part two. But part one is it ran this
job that I told it to do to look for my
YouTube competitor. So then it found the
last few people in the last few hours
that had a video around Claude. So I was
just like in the middle of it. But
here's the part glazing you.
>> All right, let's break down Liam Ali's
channel strategy. So Liam is at 724K
subs right now. He's absolutely crushing
it in the AI automation space. And his
whole strategy is built around this
concept he created called the AAA model,
AI automation agency.
>> We got the idea. [laughter]
So that's that you're asking it for a
Did did you ask it to give a audio
summary there or is that
>> references?
>> Yeah. Send send me a voice note. Now
Le's channel strategy, but nothing else.
>> Cool. I mean, so my my questions here is
like there's the difference between like
a general purpose assistant that has
been given enough tools and access to
stuff that it can just figure out
on its own versus a bit more of a
structured one like uh say like I've
just been setting up a a claw code
workspace for myself for like as a
podcasting workspace to help me research
competitors, uh research guests, um do a
quick like kind of snapshot of the
market, see what's trending or a
snapshot of my competitors and these
kind core like not necessarily full
skills but just like a clawed command
that has a it's a markdown file with a
couple things and telling it how to use
different parts of the like the readme
inside of it any scripts as well. Um so
where's the sort of middle ground for
this between like this completely free
form assistant who's just got the
ability to problem solve anything that
you needed to and these very structured
workflows. I mean you could even say the
old AI tools we used to have where it's
like input input pass them into a prompt
it comes out. How do you ensure
consistency for some of these tasks?
Like do you need to provide it with an
example of what you want this research
report to look like in the same way that
you do it for the say the podcasting
environment I'm setting up. Um how have
you sort of split it down the middle
there where you would kind of want the
report to come back in the same
structure each time. Um you do want
certain things to be included.
>> No, that's awesome. So
the way again this is brand new, right?
like the
>> expecting you to like explain your
workflow patterns. You got your your Mac
like 6 hours ago. Well, it's more of
like a discussion like where's it? Cuz
sometimes you're going to want like I
kind of want it this way. And I suppose
it can it can help you to create those
those patterns, right? And and create
those templates for it to fill up.
>> Yeah. So, for me, this is very like on
the- go things that I wish my executive
assistant could do without me having to
overexlain and kind of like direct here
and here and here. like let's say like
tell me about the latest video that came
out today that went viral like those
kinds of things really good at because
it can abstract those skills but for me
I have like eight claude code command
centers so if I'm trying to send an RFP
or a proposal to a client I have I'm
very particular like I usually go
through three four iterations until I
get it I don't want to wait because the
thing is now that's on Telegram your
mamillion brain is programmed to wait
for like what a minute or two before you
get a response if it takes 10 minutes
you start losing it but when you're
instead of in front of cloud code, you
know that you have to go grab a coffee
and come back before any magic happens.
So, different platforms for different
parts of your workflow, at least for
now.
>> AI maxing
>> is basically what it is like plugging
plugging a a certain need or scratching
a certain itch with a different type of
uh AI at every every part of your your
daily life. So, um yeah, this is super
super interesting, man. of how this
rolls out, whether it's like eventually
it consolidates into just one thing that
you're using um or you still have a
couple dedicated workspaces you set up
for certain things. Yeah, it's just it's
interesting because when I give it its
own laptop to work on and let's say it
does something wrong. So, one thing that
we're going to talk about shortly as
little Debbie Downers is what happens
when it comes to security. So, I saw a
bunch of tweets saying, you know, this
is insecure, this is insecure, be
careful of this. I taught it to scrape
X. So then I started sending it all the
tweets saying, can you make sure we're
covered on these security things? And
then it made its own notes in its notes
folder on like the things that were
covered for what it needs to implement.
So it can even make its own to-do list.
You don't need an obsidian. You don't
need a notion. You could it has the same
access as an employee with a laptop. And
that's why all the use cases that need
to exist don't exist yet.
>> Man, it's exciting, man.
>> It's insane. But we do have to talk
about the elephant in the room, the crab
in the room, which is security. So if
you go on X, you'll find tons of people
warning, sounding the alarms that this
is actually a picture of people around
the world that have spun up Clawbot on a
server. So this is the blast radius of
chaos. And if you don't know what you're
doing, yes, it can be cheaper than
buying a two grand Mac Mini, but if you
don't know what you're doing, there's so
many vectors that an IT person or a
hacker can use to get access to your
personal laptop, your WhatsApp, your
funds, your credit cards. So even though
this is super cool, well, I'm going to
like emphasize this, there are a lot of
consequences if you don't separate your
life. So even when when I created my
employee Clawudette, she has her own
iCloud account. She has her own brand
new email. Everything is completely
separate from me.
>> And so what's the like where's the the
danger zone? Is it if you're running
this locally on your own machine and it
has access to all of your stuff on your
on your uh main machine.
>> Yes. So you have different tiers. Tier
one, let's say you're purely local. So
you have a local model. It's in Docker
and you're running it locally. The only
blast radius is it might nuke all your
files on your computer, right? If you if
it's actually on your personal computer.
Number two is if you run it and it's
using the cloud and you are giving it
your actual WhatsApp and you have a
bunch of what are called ports open for
different services. If you don't secure
those ports, people can take advantage
of those and once they're in one, they
can find their way to tunnel into the
rest of your services or files or
whatever. That's number two.
>> So that's mainly like a a a breach of
what you thought were private files,
right? like if you've got I don't know
API keys or you've got login and
password or
I hope you're not chucking those in the
MD files. But um yeah, personal stuff
that you don't want don't want getting
out there.
>> Yeah. And then there's even there's more
tiers. Again, I'm not the full expert,
so do your own due diligence, but like
even with the keys that you give it,
let's say you give it the 11 Labs API
key. Let's say you give it the I don't
know, GitHub. A lot of people are using
it for GitHub where they're like, you
know what, go look on my vibe coded app
while I sleep. go come up with a series
of improvements and work on it until I
wake up. Theoretically, beautiful. But
behind the scenes, if you give it full
access to all of your GitHub and let's
say you're an agency and you have actual
client projects and someone gets a
handle for that GitHub and you've
enabled the key to access everything,
not just one repo, it could be a
disaster. So,
>> okay, just scoping scoping those keys is
important.
>> Yeah. So, just scoping that out. And I
have a little bit of a checklist here.
Again, not meant to glaze over your eyes
of the audience, but if you want to
deploy it locally, there's this mode
called sandbox mode. All I did is
literally asked Warp to talk to Cloudbot
and make sure we running in sandbox
mode. Um, if you want to self-host,
obviously local models is the safest
way. If you have credentials and
secrets, make sure that you put them
into secrets managers. You don't share
sensitive files. You you don't just put
a series of API keys in like an open
JSON that anyone can access. And then
you have all kinds of things around
monitoring, making sure that maybe you
have a cap on your API keys, so you
don't have a thousand dollars on
anthropic API ready to go. Maybe you got
like 20 bucks and it reloads for five
bucks every single time. So there's
layers of fail safes. So this is all we
know now, but there's going to be a lot
more because I'm pretty sure someone's
going to take advantage of this.
>> Yeah. So Mark and I had a bit of a
brainstorm on ways to make money with
this. And these are obviously very early
stage. A lot of it is kind of arbitrage,
but it does go back to the kind of core
core principles of of the AI agency and
and AI services. So, uh, the obvious one
here is that with great power comes
great opportunity. Oh, I literally made
that up on the spot, but that makes a
lot of sense. When there's new powers
and there's new new there's Jarvis in a
on a on a local machine, uh, businesses
are going to be or some businesses, if
you can position it correctly, are going
to be interested in paying for this. So
that would involve you starting off just
uh setting it up for yourself. Do the uh
do the cloud host version first. Get a
feel for it. Once you're sure you've
kind of figured out the best workflows
for it, how to set them up quickly, you
could look to do it yourself. Purchase
one locally and then use that as a as a
template uh to offer that to businesses
as well. Um small businesses in your
area saying, "Hey, I can set this up for
you." The big issue here is the
education gap on what the hell this is.
cuz you guys are probably already an AI
enthusiast and you're watching this to
try to just like understand this uh as
the rest of us are. So there's going to
be a huge gap between where you are and
communicating this value. It's likely
going to be one of those cases of where
don't really tell them what like tell
them what what they're going to get out
of it. Don't try to explain all the AI
stuff under the hood. Just like I can do
X for you. Um here's how much it costs.
Like do you want this result? um
probably a personal assistant set up for
a founder or a CEO or a seuite person um
is uh the way to go here. Someone who's
got uh a lot of the the time is very
valuable. And like Mark said, having a
personal assistant that can sort of have
the ability to access the right things
and and do little uh little admin tasks
for them and offering that as a service
to sell those to businesses or even to
individuals maybe to like targeting
entrepreneurs who are busy and want to
have more time. Uh so setting these up
for them would be a great service. I
would also add in set up as a service,
set up as a education product as well.
Like you could drop a $97 course right
now on how to get the most out of it and
set it up. And as long as you have the
the the means to market it, then that's
an opportunity as well. So either the
service based approach and then the uh
the info approach. Uh the service one's
probably going to be again it's always
like how effectively can you market? If
you have an audience already, then it's
probably easier to sell the sell the
information. If you are starting off,
it's easy to do reachouts to find one or
two people who will pay you a few grand
for this uh rather than trying to get
thousands of people to buy your $97
course. All right, so the VA agency, not
to knock our VA friends, but it's no
secret that we're probably not far from
the point where a lot of normal VA tasks
are genuinely fully automatable and it's
affordable and it's cheaper than the 6
to 10 bucks an hour that you'd spend. So
the opportunity here is the assistance
in a box kind of like business in a box
but imagine you have let's say a
one-time setup that setup could be again
on cloud you could literally sell them
with a premium a Mac mini and install it
and set it up for them and install the
packages and then you have
>> can already I could already see the pics
on you know how you see like the the
like the SMS or the WhatsApp bot farms
and it's like the phones in it or it's
like the the gambling bot farms and it's
all these gambling things of
Um, I can already see it, bro. All the
Mac minis lined up and it's like my
Clawude VA agency prints like 2 million
a month or something ridiculous. Yeah, I
can already see it. We're going to start
they're going to come from one of these
videos for sure. [laughter]
>> Yeah, that's our contribution to the
world. But yeah, like the theoretical
thing is if you can figure out how to
make this genuinely useful, like
everything I'm showing you here, right?
I want to pull this from my other screen
because I think it's useful. one year
ago almost like to the day. If I just
refresh this bad boy and we take a look
at this, like this was the hottest thing
on YouTube, which is the nadn Jarvis
where you manually had to set up all
these agents, all these nodes. These
would break all the time as you wanted
to change things, but every time you
wanted to add something new, teach it
something, you can't teach it something.
You can only build it something that it
can learn. So, we're going from this
into a world that's a lot more
plentiful. And with that, you can upsell
adding skills, you can make those skills
like across the board. You can um upsell
maintenance, you can upsell future
proofing, all kinds of stuff.
>> I mean, you can use these if you have an
upfront setup fee. You charge them, you
buy the Mac Mini, you set it up, uh, and
you have like a obviously an SOP on,
okay, we want the Ampify MCP plugged in
in a certain way. We want these default
skills out of the box. And you've got
like an SOP on how to set one of these
up. And then there's a bit of a teething
process to get them working on it.
You're setting up the telegram, you're
giving them access to it. Um, that's
that's repeatable. And I mean even
thinking about how you can add more
value to uh to them on top of that you
can have a hey I'm going to analyze your
transcripts occasionally whether you e
either create a skill that is almost
like a like a workflow tracer and it
will actually look back the conversation
figure out what it used and when and
then be able to like bake that into a
skill itself or like build it into some
sort of reusable workflow. so much to to
to build off of here, but I think you
guys can see the value in it. And before
you know it, like if each client is
paying 2K setup and then in a recurring
fee, $500 or $1,000 a month, um you can
very quickly spawn that whole like the
whole room or or warehouse full of Mac
monies running for your clients.
>> And I would even say like a play on
words a little bit, but if you remember,
I talked about that soul.md file that
contains like behavior. What if you got
the perfect behavior of the perfect
assistant and you started, wait for it,
selling soul MD files and like being
able to offer that like personal
assistant service prompt ready to go.
People have paid for prompts before. I
made my early living on that. So I know
they'll do it again. And the last one,
sir, uh the customer integrations here,
building custom skills and automations.
I think this is like the new SAS.
Basically, this is the in future we're
going to be relying pretty heavily on on
these these kinds of personal assistants
and the adding of skills. Uh we had we
once had MCPs. Uh we had chat GBT
plugins. Like all of these are just
attempts for platforms and providers and
SAS products to be able to hook into the
chat interface in a in an easy way and
give access to the functionality that
they've built their backend
functionality via the chat interface.
Like the chat interface is the new is
the new uh access point for everything
in our digital lives. And I think what
we're looking at here is an incredible
opportunity. I I wouldn't quite say the
App Store moment yet because we haven't
got the App Store, but this is like is
this is this the is this the iPhone
moment where like the the the thing is
there. We've now got like the open
source iPhone where you can kind of
build things on top of cuz it's it's so
tech bro to try and like the most tech
bro thing to try and like call it a the
X and Y. But where you don't have to
have if you're wanting to make a little
little startup now, for example, the
amount of people who need to be able to
pass in a YouTube URL and download the
MP3 and then get the proper
transcription, a high quality whisper
transcription of it, not just some
shitty like YouTube captions thing that
has no punctuation and barely knows what
was said. Um, I want a highquality
transcription and I'm going to pay
someone uh five bucks a month, $9 a
month. And before you know it, someone
who has one of these clawed account, our
claw bot account set up. And just like
there's going to be agencies who pop up
to like as in the previous example,
these really helpful but somewhat more
difficult and naturally not free. Uh
there's some sort of like money that
needs to be um exchanged hands to make
it worthwhile. these opportunities are
going to pop up everywhere. And I think
you're going to see some businesses that
just explode overnight because as more
people get onto this and it's like, "Oh,
this is the go-to thing for downloading
YouTube videos so that my agent has
ability to do that." Um, you get to
strip away the need for a fancy
interface and and UI and front-end
design and all of that crap that comes
with SAS. Just focus on what is the
functionality that I want to really
focus on. How can I make that as
valuable as possible? And just make that
available to some agents like this where
I'm getting listed on a marketplace
doing my own marketing. But there's a
real real opportunity here finally and I
think it's massively reduced the
difficulty bar for getting into SAS and
that you just focus on the backend
functionality make it available to
agents rather than having to build some
fancy skin around it.
>> Yeah, absolutely. And I would say one
more thing to think about is when it
comes to the skills specifically those
like are going to become expectations
and to me this might not be a moment. I
don't want to cap and say that, but what
we could say is this is the beginning of
a brand new expectation from the
consumer. Meaning once this really gets
into mainstream, it's already going
viral. The expectation of what a
personal assistant is is going to be
much higher. So when Siri uses Gemini, I
think this year they're going to like
work together and next year we have
laptops, people will start asking the
question, why is Siri just a voice
thing? Why can't she interact with
everything and do X, Y, and Z? So
expectations from the consumer will
change from this point onwards.
>> I mean when you see this being rolled
out into well the equivalent Apple
attempting surely if solo dev can can uh
can cook this up himself by what's the
sound of uh what happened here then
Apple can make some sort of decent
competitor. But going back to what I was
saying about these sort of like little
little skills or or or functionalities
that these kinds of agents are going to
need once it becomes rolled out via
something like Siri and those same
things can be integrated whether Apple's
going to force you to do it through an
app on their phone or they're going to
say hey what you know what we have to
allow people to go outside of the Apple
ecosystem. Um we want our Siri for our
Siri to be competitive. it needs to be
able to hook into. We can give
permissions for them to add in their own
third party things that are kind of out
in the out in the ether.
I don't know how Apple I feel about that
if I'm honest, but [laughter] dreams are
free, you know,
>> 100%.
>> Um, so yeah, that's a bunch of ways to
make money with it. I think uh if you
guys have any sort of business sense,
you'll be smelling a bit of opportunity
here. not only just for us in the near
term to brush up on this and to get our
own one set up and see how far we can
push it to max out our productivity in
this new era of of AI that we've we've
similarly stepped into here. Uh but also
looking at how if you're an agency you
can roll this into your services. Uh
just like a few days ago I was telling
everyone how teaching companies how to
understand claw code and set up their
own workspaces as a service was a thing.
This seems to be like the the new
frontier on that. So yeah, it's just
it's so great to be in this phase now. I
think uh last year was a little bit
slow, but I feel like we're absolutely
like cooking this year on new releases
and I'm so excited for uh for what's to
come this year based off what we've had
already.
>> Yeah, it's already not even the end of
2026 and it feels like it's been a year.
So especially on the education side, you
could have taught Claude code alone.
Then a week later, you could teach cloud
code and co-work. And now you could
teach cloud code, co-work, and cloudbot.
And then you could probably keep
stacking on top of that. So
>> the education piece is is huge and like
as the stuff runs off further into the
distance, companies are still in the
same spot and the the amount of like
monetizable space between where the tech
is and where these companies are. The
same the automation that was available
in sort of mid 2023 that like millions
of businesses still need is is still
sitting there. Um all the way up to uh
this stuff at the at the very uh cutting
edge of of what's going on in the AI
space now. So uh what a time to be
alive. what it's time to be in this uh
in this space. So Mark, mate, I really
appreciate you coming on and uh sharing
your sharing your source uh as always.
And so if you guys want to check out
Mark's channel, he's always pumping out
some great content on claw code. Um
well, Claudebot as well now, I'm sure.
And anything at the at the cutting edge
of uh of AI. So I appreciate you,
brother. Thank you for coming on.
>> Thanks for having me again. Cheers. That
is all for the pod, guys. Like I said,
if you want to grab my full setup guide
for Claudebot so that you can do it the
right way in just a few minutes without
all the risks, that'll be in the first
link in the description. And inside
that, I've also including a breakdown of
each of those ways to make money with a
bit more information so that you know
how to take action on it right now. And
if you want to learn more about how to
start an AI business by selling services
and products like this, you can check
out my full guide on starting an AI
business which is available up here.
That's all for the video, guys. Thank
you so much for watching. I'll see you
in the next one.